// this contains questions related to all schemes and initiative undertaken and promoted by FSSAI whether alone or collaborate with others.



const eatrightindia = [

]

const eatrightquestionbank1 = [
    // this following set is taken from fssai which made a alexa based eat right quiz
    { // 144
        question: "Deficiency of which vitamin is associated  with Neural Tube Defects?",
        answers: ["Vitamin B3", "Vitamin B6", "Vitamin B9", "Vitamin B12"],
        correct: "Vitamin B9"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the name of the Co-enzyme Q10?",
        answers: ["carenone", "Ubiquinone", "quinone", "none of above"],
        correct: "Ubiquinone"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the scientific name of Vitamin  B10?",
        answers: ["BCAA", "PABA", "ALA", "none of above"],
        correct: "PABA"
    },
    {
        question: "Brewer's yeast is rich in which mineral?",
        answers: ["iron", "phosphorous", "chromium", "none of above"],
        correct: "chromium"
    },
    { // 140
        question: "Deficiency of which vitamin causes  alcohol related neuro disorder?",
        answers: ["Wernicke Korsakoff disease", "fetal alcohol syndrome", "riboflavinosis", "none of above"],
        correct: "none of above"
    },
    {
        question: "What percentage of milk fat is present in  standardized milk?",
        answers: ["3.50%", "3.75%", "4.25%", "4.50%"],
        correct: "3.50%"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a reducing sugar?",
        answers: ["Starch", "Lactose", "Maltose", "Fructose"],
        correct: "Fructose"
    },
    {
        question: "Vitamin D is chemically known as?",
        answers: ["calciferol", "tocopherol", "glutamic acid", "niacin"],
        correct: "calciferol"
    },
    {
        question: "Which among the following has the  highest Glycemic Index?",
        answers: ["Grapes", "Mango", "Orange", "Water melon"],
        correct: "Water melon"
    },
    {
        question: "what is end product of enyzymatic  browning?",
        answers: ["melanins", "galactose", "dextrin", "all of the above"],
        correct: "melanins"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the one monosaccharide which  does not occur naturally in foods or  beverages?",
        answers: ["fructose", "lecithin", "beta carotene", "galactose"],
        correct: "galactose"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the caloric content of alcohol?",
        answers: ["9 calories per gram", "28 calories per gram", "7 calories per gram", "4 calories per gram"],
        correct: "7 calories per gram"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the three minerals present in the  greatest amounts in cereal grains like  wheat, millet and brown rice?",
        answers: ["sodium, carbonate, bisulfate", "zinc, mercury, copper", "calcium, iron, phosphorous", "potassium, magnesium, calcium"],
        correct: "potassium, magnesium, calcium"
    },
    {
        question: "Omega 3 fatty acid is also known by what  other name?",
        answers: ["olive oil", "linolenic acid", "fish oil", "lenoleic acid"],
        correct: "linolenic acid"
    },
    { // 130
        question: "Select an appropriate meal for an obese  person?",
        answers: ["Mix vegetable + Roasted  chicken+ Whole wheat flour  chapatti", "Dal makhni + Fried chicken +  Rumali roti", "Burger + fries+ coke", "Biryani + curd"],
        correct: "Mix vegetable + Roasted  chicken+ Whole wheat flour  chapatti"
    },
    {
        question: "A healthier vegetable to select for a  diabetic is?",
        answers: ["Colocasia", "Spinach", "Potato", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Colocasia"
    },
    {
        question: "A deficiency of iodine may lead to which  of these?",
        answers: ["Endemic goitre", "Hypothyroidism", "Cretinism", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What should be reduced in diet to  prevent hypertension?",
        answers: ["Salt", "Fibrous food", "Green Vegetables", "Fruits"],
        correct: "Salt"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is a metabolic disorder  characterized by high blood pressure?",
        answers: ["Osteoporosis", "Cardiovascular disease", "Osteopenia", "Sugar"],
        correct: "Cardiovascular disease"
    },
    {
        question: "Diabetics are at increased risk of heart  disease if they also?",
        answers: ["Smoke", "Have high HDL cholesterol levels", "Are physically active", "Consume a high-fiber diet"],
        correct: "Smoke"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following health benefits  would result from regular walking?",
        answers: ["Increased blood pressure", "Decreased risk of heart  disease", "Increased resting heart rate ", "Decreased life  expectancy"],
        correct: "Decreased risk of heart  disease"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these fats can increase your risk  of heart disease?",
        answers: ["Polyunsaturated fats", "Monounsaturated fats", "Monounsaturated fats and  polyunsaturated fats", "Trans fats and saturated fats"],
        correct: "Trans fats and saturated fats"
    },
    {
        question: "What's are the best diet to follow?",
        answers: ["Paleo", "Vegan", "Low carb", "The diet that works  best for them"],
        correct: "The diet that works  best for them"
    },
    {
        question: "The number of calories you can eat each  day without gaining weight depends on  your?",
        answers: ["Hunger", "Activity level", "Environment", "Appetite"],
        correct: "Activity level"
    },
    {// 120
        question: "Which of the following has the highest  glycemix index?",
        answers: ["Ice cream", "cucumber", "bread", "Dextrose"],
        correct: "Dextrose"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the scientific term for a disease that causes dizziness?",
        answers: ["Diabetes", "Stroke", "Vertigo", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Vertigo"
    },
    {
        question: "Percentage of acetic acid in commercially  available vinegar is?",
        answers: ["2%", "4%", "6%", "10%"],
        correct: "4%"
    },
    {
        question: "Process of moisture adjustment in wheat  is?",
        answers: ["Cleaning", "Flour formation", "Separation of endosperm", "Wheat conditioning"],
        correct: "Wheat conditioning"
    },
    {
        question: "soft cheese made by curdling soy milk  with a coagulant is?",
        answers: ["Tempeh", "Tofu", "Yogurt", "Cheddar"],
        correct: "Tofu"
    },
    {
        question: "Most widely known by-product of corn  processing is?",
        answers: ["Glue", "Paint", "Ethanol", "Lotion"],
        correct: "Ethanol"
    },
    {
        question: "Microwave is ionizing or non-ionizing  radiation?",
        answers: ["ionizing", "Non-ionizing", "both", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Non-ionizing"
    },
    {
        question: "The standard size of fat globules of  homogenized milk is?",
        answers: ["0.2-2 micrometer", "0.5-4 micrometer", "3-5 micrometer", "7-10 micrometer"],
        correct: "0.2-2 micrometer"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Sodium Cyclamate as a food additive?",
        answers: ["Artifical Sweetner", "Coloring agent", "Thickening agent", "None of these"],
        correct: "Artifical Sweetner"
    },
    {
        question: "Natto is fermented product made from?",
        answers: ["soyabean", "rice", "grapes", "None of these"],
        correct: "soyabean"
    },
    { // 110
        question: "Which GM variety of rice has enhanced beta carotenes and iron?",
        answers: ["Golden Rice", "Brown rice", "Par Boiled Rice", "None of these"],
        correct: "Golden Rice"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is a water soluble natural pigment?",
        answers: ["Anthocyanin", "Chlorophyll", "Carotenoid", "None of these"],
        correct: "Anthocyanin"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Sodium Cyclamate as a food additive?",
        answers: ["Artificial Sweetener", "Coloring agent", "Thickening agent", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Artificial Sweetener"
    },
    {
        question: "During malting, barley and other grains are broken down by?",
        answers: ["Heating to 95 degree Celsius", "Conditioning", "Amylases", "Yeasts"],
        correct: "Amylases"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the mixture of probiotics and prebiotics called?",
        answers: ["Symbiotics", "Dibiotics", "Synbiotics", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Synbiotics"
    },
    {
        question: "The principal flavouring agent of butter is?",
        answers: ["Diacetal", "sodium", "diacetae", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Diacetal"
    },
    {
        question: "Shitake is a type of?",
        answers: ["Mushroom", "Apple", "potato", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Mushroom"
    },
    {
        question: "Products that contain live micro organism  in sufficient numbers to promote intestinal microbial balance?",
        answers: ["Antibiotics", "Probiotics", "Prebiotics", "Digestive enzyme"],
        correct: "Probiotics"
    },
    {
        question: "Which egg white protein has antibacterial  property?",
        answers: ["Conalbumin", "Avidin", "Ovomuin", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Conalbumin"
    },
    {
        question: "Carrageenan is extracted from?",
        answers: ["soyabean", "Milk", "Red edible sea weed", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Red edible sea weed"
    },
    { // 100
        question: "Sauerkraut is a fermented product made of?",
        answers: ["cabbage", "cuccumber", "soyabean", "rice"],
        correct: "cabbage"
    },
    {
        question: "Koji is a fermented product made from?",
        answers: ["cabbage", "cuccumber", "soyabean", "rice"],
        correct: "soyabean"
    },
    {
        question: "Liquid fraction obtained during mashing  in beer making is called as?",
        answers: ["Malt", "Wart", "Wort", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Wort"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is essential for preventing  dental caries?",
        answers: ["Flouride", "Calcium", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Flouride"
    },
    {
        question: "Milk is a poor source of?",
        answers: ["Calcium", "Protein", "Carbohydrate", "Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Vitamin C"
    },
    {
        question: "Amla is a good source of which Vitamin?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin K"],
        correct: "Vitamin C"
    },
    {
        question: "Micro-mineral essential for production of thyroid hormone is?",
        answers: ["Calcium", "Iodine", "Fluorine", "Magnesium"],
        correct: "Iodine"
    },
    {
        question: "Most common polysaccharide added to food is?",
        answers: ["Water", "Salt", "Glucose", "Starch"],
        correct: "Starch"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the major protein of muscle fibre of meat?",
        answers: ["Myosin", "Leucine", "Albumin", "Globulin"],
        correct: "Myosin"
    },
    {
        question: "Tocopherol is used in foods as?",
        answers: ["Acidity regulator", "Stabilizer", "Antioxidant", "Emulsifier"],
        correct: "Antioxidant"
    },
    { // 90
        question: "Weight gained per gram of protein  consumed is known as?",
        answers: ["BV", "NPU", "PER", "NPR"],
        correct: "PER"
    },
    {
        question: "Coloustrum is very good as it is rich in?",
        answers: ["Protein and carbohydrate", "Proteins and antibodies", "Minerals and vitamins", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Chemically, fats and oils are what type of glycerides?",
        answers: ["Monoglycerides", "Triglycerides", "Diglycerides", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Triglycerides"
    },
    {
        question: "Minimum percentage of milk fat required  for cream is?",
        answers: ["25%", "30%", "35%", "45%"],
        correct: "25%"
    },
    {
        question: "Pernicious anaemia is caused by  deficiency of?",
        answers: ["Iron", "Folic acid", "Vitamin B 12", "Vitamin A"],
        correct: "Vitamin B 12"
    },
    {
        question: "How much Milk Fat Skimmed milk contains?",
        answers: ["1.5%", "3.5%", "0.5%", "3.0 %"],
        correct: "0.5%"
    },
    {
        question: "As per FSS Act, maximum fortification of iodine in table salt is?",
        answers: ["10 ppm", "15 ppm", "20 ppm", "30 ppm"],
        correct: "30 ppm"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of HFCS with reference to  sweeteners?",
        answers: ["High Fructose Corn Syrup", "High Fat Corn Substitute", "High Frying Corn Substitute", "None of the above"],
        correct: "High Fructose Corn Syrup"
    },
    {
        question: "Which poisoning causes minamata disease?",
        answers: ["lead", "Mercury", "Iron", "Silver"],
        correct: "Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "Primary source of energy utilized by human body?",
        answers: ["Carbohydrate/sugar", "fats", "Proteins", "Fiber"],
        correct: "Carbohydrate/sugar"
    },
    { // 80
        question: "Chemical name for vitamin B3?",
        answers: ["Niacin", "Cyanocobalmin", "Carotene", "Methionine"],
        correct: "Niacin"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Vitamin is hydroxocobalamin?",
        answers: ["B2", "B6", "B12", "B3"],
        correct: "B12"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of PUFA?",
        answers: ["Poly unsaturated fatty acids", "Poly Unhealthy Fatty Acids", "Poly unused fats and acids", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Poly unsaturated fatty acids"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of ALA is ?",
        answers: ["Alpha linolenic acid", "Alpha linoleic acid", "Alpha long -chain acid", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Alpha linolenic acid"
    },
    {
        question: "Thiamine deficiency leads to which  disease?",
        answers: ["Rickets", "Jaundice", "Beriberi", "Scurvy"],
        correct: "Beriberi"
    },
    {
        question: "FSSAI has introduced which logo for  fortified staple food products?",
        answers: ["+Z Logo", "+F logo", "+R logo", "None of the above"],
        correct: "+F logo"
    },
    {
        question: "What does Vitamin K deficiency lead to?",
        answers: ["Problem in digestion", "Problem in Blood  Coagulation", "Problem in Calcium  Metabolism", "All the three"],
        correct: "Problem in Blood  Coagulation"
    },
    {
        question: "According to the My pyramid food  Guidance system, a person's should  obtain most of their fat from?",
        answers: ["Beef, chicken and fish", "Vegetables oils, nuts and fish", "Fats, oils, and sweet", "Milk, yogurt and  cheese"],
        correct: "Vegetables oils, nuts and fish"
    },
    {
        question: "The deficiency of which of the following  group of nutrients affects the skin?",
        answers: ["Iron, Iodine, Zinc, Potassium", "Riboflacin, Niacin,  Pyridoxine, Pantothenic Acid", "Vitamin K, Calcium, Fluorine,  Copper", "All the three"],
        correct: "Riboflacin, Niacin,  Pyridoxine, Pantothenic Acid"
    },
    {
        question: "Your body needs vitamins and minerals because?",
        answers: ["They gives the body energy", "They help to carry out metabolic rates", "They insulate the body's organs", "They withdraw heat from the body"],
        correct: "They help to carry out metabolic rates"
    },
    { // 70
        question: "All of the following are nutrients found in food except?",
        answers: ["Plasma", "Proteins", "Carbohydrates", "Vitamins"],
        correct: "Plasma"
    },
    {
        question: "A substance needed by the body for  growth, energy, repair and maintenance  is called?",
        answers: ["Nutrient", "Carbohydrates", "Calorie", "Fatty acid"],
        correct: "Nutrient"
    },
    {
        question: "Flavouring compound of Orange is?",
        answers: ["limonene", "shagol", "geraniol", "carvone"],
        correct: "limonene"
    },
    {
        question: "Overcome the deficiency of nutrients from a synthetic source is called?",
        answers: ["fermentation", "supplementation", "fortification", "none of above"],
        correct: "supplementation"
    },
    {
        question: "variety of wheat is used for  manufacturing of pasta?",
        answers: ["Soft wheat", "Hard wheat", "Durum wheat", "White wheat"],
        correct: "Durum wheat"
    },
    {
        question: "Bean used for the extraction of gum is?",
        answers: ["Broad bean", "Cluster bean", "French bean", "Hyacinth bean"],
        correct: "Cluster bean"
    },
    {
        question: "Top two minerals in milk are?",
        answers: ["iron and calcium", "calcium and folic acid", "calcium and phosphorous", "none of above"],
        correct: "calcium and phosphorous"
    },
    {
        question: "ATP stands for?",
        answers: ["adenosine Tri Phosphate", "adenosine triphosphorous", "adenosine Di-Phosphate", "none of above"],
        correct: "adenosine Tri Phosphate"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the most fermentable sugar?",
        answers: ["Sucrose", "Glucose", "Maltose", "Fructose"],
        correct: "Glucose"
    },
    {
        question: "Incidental additives include?",
        answers: ["Fats in the form of shortening", "Minerals from cooking vessels", "Substances that are a major  energy contributor to the food", "Substances often used at home, such as garlic"],
        correct: "Minerals from cooking vessels"
    },
    { // 60
        question: "Monosodium glutamate is used in food  industry as?",
        answers: ["Flavour enhancer", "Colour enhancer", "Texture enhancer", "Appearance enhancer"],
        correct: "Flavour enhancer"
    },
    {
        question: "Chemical name for Vitamin B1?",
        answers: ["beri-beri", "niacin", "thiamine", "folic acid"],
        correct: "thiamine"
    },
    {
        question: "Unit of Protein Efficiency is?",
        answers: ["weight gain per gram of protein", "weight gain per gram of fat", "weight gain per gram of carbohydrates", "none of these"],
        correct: "weight gain per gram of protein"
    },
    {
        question: "Vitamin necessary for blood coagulation is?",
        answers: ["Vitamin D", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin B", "Vitamin K"],
        correct: "Vitamin K"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of MUFA?",
        answers: ["monoultrasaturated fatty  acids", "multi unsaturated fatty acids", "Mono Unsaturated Fatty  Acids", "none of above"],
        correct: "Mono Unsaturated Fatty  Acids"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the protein present in Maize?",
        answers: ["Avidin", "Albumen", "Gluten", "Zein"],
        correct: "Zein"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is not a water soluble vitamin?",
        answers: ["Biotin", "Thiamine", "Retinol", "Niacin"],
        correct: "Retinol"
    },
    {
        question: "What does the bile digest in the small intestine?",
        answers: ["Proteins", "Fats", "Carbohydrates", "Minerals"],
        correct: "Fats"
    },
    {
        question: "1 gm of alcohol gives how much calories?",
        answers: ["5", "6", "7", "8"],
        correct: "7"
    },
    {
        question: "Lycopene is a?",
        answers: ["Enzyme", "Amino acid", "Pigment", "Vitamin"],
        correct: "Pigment"
    },
    { // 50
        question: "Which dietary component helps to maintain a constant body temperature in our body?",
        answers: ["Roughage", "Vitamins", "Water", "Energy giving food"],
        correct: "Water"
    },
    {
        question: "This nutrient helps insulate our body and cushion our organs?",
        answers: ["Water", "Calcium", "Potassium", "Fat"],
        correct: "Fat"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the function of vitamin K in our body?",
        answers: ["Good vision", "Smooth skin", "Blood clotting", "RBC formation"],
        correct: "Blood clotting"
    },
    {
        question: "Salt is iodized to prevent?",
        answers: ["Marasmus", "Goitre", "Pellagra", "Anaemia"],
        correct: "Goitre"
    },
    {
        question: "Salt is iodized to prevent?",
        answers: ["Adenosine tri phosphate", "Albumin tri phosphate", "Amino tri phosphate", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Adenosine tri phosphate",
        description: "doubt"
    },
    {
        question: "ATP stands for?",
        answers: ["Adenosine tri phosphate", "Albumin tri phosphate", "Amino tri phosphate", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Adenosine tri phosphate"
    },
    {
        question: "Vitamin necessary for blood coagulation  is?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin E", "Vitamin K"],
        correct: "Vitamin K"
    },
    {
        question: "In onion, purple colour is due to?",
        answers: ["Anthocyanin", "Chlorophyll", "Carotenoid", "None of these"],
        correct: "Anthocyanin"
    },
    {
        question: "1 gm of fat gives how many calories?",
        answers: ["8", "9", "10", "11"],
        correct: "9"
    },
    {
        question: "Vitamin B9 is commonly known as?",
        answers: ["Thiamine", "Riboflavin", "Folic acid", "Ascorbic acid"],
        correct: "Folic acid"
    },
    { // 40
        question: "Which one is a water soluble Vitamin?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin E", "Vitamin D"],
        correct: "Vitamin C"
    },
    {
        question: "Deficiency of Vitamin A leads to?",
        answers: ["Obesity", "High BP", "Night Blindness", "High Cholesterol"],
        correct: "Night Blindness"
    },
    {
        question: "Fibre is important to facilitate which function in the body?",
        answers: ["Provide energy", "Absorb nutrients", "Bowel movements", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Bowel movements"
    },
    {
        question: "Kwashiorkor is caused by deficiency of?",
        answers: ["Vitamin K", "Proteins", "Calcium", "Fats"],
        correct: "Proteins"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the main dietary source of vitamin K?",
        answers: ["Green leafy vegetables", "Milk", "Cheese", "Pulses"],
        correct: "Green leafy vegetables"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is not a nutrient?",
        answers: ["Vitamins", "Minerals", "Fibre", "Fats"],
        correct: "Fibre"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is the best source of energy for us?",
        answers: ["Meat group", "Fats, oils and sweets", "Bread and cereals", "Milk and cheese"],
        correct: "Bread and cereals"
    },
    {
        question: "Which nutrient is most needed for structural components of the body?",
        answers: ["Carbohydrates", "Protein", "Fats", "Fiber"],
        correct: "Protein"
    },
    {
        question: "What is known as the sunshine vitamin?",
        answers: ["Vitamin D", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin K", "Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Vitamin D"
    },
    {
        question: "1 gm of carbohydrate gives how much  calories?",
        answers: ["4", "5", "6", "7"],
        correct: "4"
    },
    { // 30
        question: "Main protein in egg white is?",
        answers: ["PR-albumin", "Ovalbumin", "Whey", "Complete"],
        correct: "Ovalbumin"
    },
    {
        question: "Which Vitamin is called as Phylloquinone?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin K", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D"],
        correct: "Vitamin K"
    },
    {
        question: "Water soluble vitamins include?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A and D", "Vitamin A and B", "Vitamin B and C", "Vitamin C and D"],
        correct: "Vitamin B and C"
    },
    {
        question: "Chemical name for Vitamin B5?",
        answers: ["Ascorbic acid", "Pantothenic acid", "Acetic acid", "Hydrocholric acid"],
        correct: "Pantothenic acid"
    },
    {
        question: "Thiamine deficiency leads to which disease?",
        answers: ["Rickets", "Jaundice", "Beriberi", "Scurvy"],
        correct: "Beriberi"
    },
    {
        question: "Carotenoids serve as precursors to which  vitamin?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin B", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D"],
        correct: "Vitamin A"
    },
    {
        question: "Term used for live bacteria found in yogurt",
        answers: ["Antibiotics", "Adjuvants", "Prebiotics", "Probiotics"],
        correct: "Probiotics"
    },
    {
        question: "Rice is fortified with which nutrient:",
        answers: ["Vitamin A and Vitamin D", "Iron, Folic Acid and Vitamin B12", "Folic acid, Vitamin B12 and  Vitamin D", "Vitamin A, Iron and  Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Iron, Folic Acid and Vitamin B12"
    },
    {
        question: "Wheat flour is fortified with which  nutrient:",
        answers: ["Vitamin A and Vitamin D", "Iron, Folic Acid and Vitamin B12", "Folic acid, Vitamin B12 and  Vitamin D", "Vitamin A, Iron and  Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Iron, Folic Acid and Vitamin B12"
    },
    {
        question: "Oil is fortified with:",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D", "Both A and D"],
        correct: "Both A and D"
    },
    { // 20
        question: "Milk is fortified with:",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin D", "Both A and D"],
        correct: "Both A and D"
    },
    {
        question: "Among the following which is the best  Source of Vitamin A:",
        answers: ["Cauliflower", "Carrot", "Beans", "None of these"],
        correct: "Carrot"
    },
    {
        question: "Blindness in young children is due to  deficiency of:",
        answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin C", "Vitamin B", "Vitamin D"],
        correct: "Vitamin A"
    },
    {
        question: "The disease caused in adults because of  deficiency of vitamin D is.",
        answers: ["Anemia", "Tuberculosis", "Osteoporosis", "Osteomalacia"],
        correct: "Osteomalacia"
    },
    {
        question: "Food fortification affects",
        answers: ["Appearance of food", "Smell of the food", "Taste of food", "No effect on organoleptic properties"],
        correct: "No effect on organoleptic properties"
    },
    {
        question: "\u0022+F\u0022 Logo stands for?",
        answers: ["Food fortification", "Organic food", "Vegetarian food", "Genetically modified  food"],
        correct: "Food fortification"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is an example of food  fortification?",
        answers: ["Adding iodine to common salt  to prevent goitre", "Adding fluoride to water to  prevent dental carries", "Adding Vitamins, A and D to  milk and oil", "All of these"],
        correct: "All of these"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following products do you  think are fortified in India?",
        answers: ["Milk and Oil", "Salt", "Wheat Flour and Rice", "All of these"],
        correct: "All of these"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Fortification of food?",
        answers: ["Deliberately increasing the  content of an essential  micronutrient in food", "Providing tablets containing  vitamins and minerals along  with food", "Proper cooking and storage  of food to avoid loss of  nutrients", "Ensuring minimum  amount of nutrients in  food"],
        correct: "Deliberately increasing the  content of an essential  micronutrient in food"
    },
    {
        question: "What is double fortified salt fortified with?",
        answers: ["Iron", "Iodine", "Iron and Iodine", "None of these"],
        correct: "Iron and Iodine"
    },
    { // 10
        question: "What is the best time to expose your body to the sunrays for producing Vitamin D?",
        answers: ["10 a.m. - 1 p.m.", "9 a.m. - 11 p.m.", "11 a.m. - 1 p.m.", "7 a.m. - 12 p.m."],
        correct: "11 a.m. - 1 p.m."
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these foods have been fortified with Vitamin D?",
        answers: ["Fortified Milk", "Fortified Oil", "Fortified Wheat Flour", "Both Fortified Milk and Fortified Oil"],
        correct: "Both Fortified Milk and Fortified Oil"
    },
    {
        question: "Is there any other nutrient besides iodine which salt is fortified with?",
        answers: ["Calcium", "Iron", "Vitamin", "Vitamin D"],
        correct: "Iron"
    },
    {
        question: "Which GM variety of rice has enhanced beta carotenes and iron.",
        answers: ["Brown Rice", "Golden Rice", "Green Rice", "None of these"],
        correct: "Golden Rice"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of GMO?",
        answers: ["Gene mutated organism", "Genome modified organism", "Genetically modified organism", "None of these"],
        correct: "Genetically modified organism"
    },
    {
        question: "What is meant by Fortification in foods",
        answers: ["Removal of 1 or more vitamins or minerals", "Addition of 1 or more vitamins or minerals", "Addition of all vitamins and minerals", "Removal of all vitamins and minerals"],
        correct: "Addition of 1 or more vitamins or minerals"
    },
    {
        question: "What is meant by Enrichment in grain products",
        answers: ["Replacement of lost vitamins and minerals", "Adding all minerals", "Removal of vitamins and  minerals", "Adding all vitamins"],
        correct: "Replacement of lost vitamins and minerals"
    },
    {
        question: "Term used for addition of nutrients to food that were not originally present ?",
        answers: ["Food Enrichment", "Food Fortification", "Food Diversifiaction", "None of these"],
        correct: "Food Enrichment"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of NOEL?",
        answers: ["Negative Observable Effect  Level", "No Observable Effect Level", "No Observable Efficiency  Level", "None of these"],
        correct: "No Observable Effect Level"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of ADI is?",
        answers: ["Acceptable Daily Intake", "Altered Daily Intake", "Acceptable Diet Intake", "None of these"],
        correct: "Acceptable Daily Intake"
    },
    
]



const eatrightquestionbank2 = [
    // this following set is taken from fssai which made a alexa based eat right quiz
    { // 59
        question: "Which of the following methods is used  for Food fortification?",
        answers: ["Mass fortification", "Universal fortification", "Targeted Fortification", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Fortification?",
        answers: ["Fortification is the addition of  nutrient to food to improve  the quality of the diet of a  group, community or a  population", "Addition of a nutrient to a  staple or other widely  consumed primary food  deficient in one or more  nutrients, to improve, the  nutritional quality of the  food", "Restore nutrients lost during  processing of foods so that  the nutrient content is  resolved to a level originally  present in the raw food", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "At present, there is no effective medical  treatment against food allergies.  Therefore, the best way for prevention is  to?",
        answers: ["Be label and ingredient alert", "Strict avoidance of the food  containing the allergen", "Use of Hypoallergenic foods", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Which chemical is released in the body in  response to allergens?",
        answers: ["Histamine", "Epinephrine", "Thyroxine", "Serotonin"],
        correct: "Histamine"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of FSMS?",
        answers: ["Food Safety Management  System", "Food Security Management  Systems", "Food Safety and  Management Systems", "Food Safety and  Marketing System"],
        correct: "Food Safety Management  System"
    },
    {
        question: "Expand HACCP?",
        answers: ["Hazard Analysis and Critical  Control Point", "Hygiene Analytics and  Critical Care Prevention", "Health Analysis and Critical  Control Point", "Hazard and Critical  Control Point"],
        correct: "Hazard Analysis and Critical  Control Point"
    },
    {
        question: "What does AGMARK stand for?",
        answers: ["Agricultural Mark", "Agri Marketing", "Agricultural Management", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Agricultural Mark"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of GAP?",
        answers: ["Good Agricultural Practices", "Good Administration Practices", "Good Association Practices", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Good Agricultural Practices"
    },
    {
        question: "What bis the full form of GMP?",
        answers: ["Good Managerial Practices", "Good Management Practices", "Good Manufacturing  Practices", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Good Manufacturing  Practices"
    },
    { // 50
        question: "Full form of GHP?",
        answers: ["Good Hygiene Practices", "Good Housekeeping  Practices", "Good Health Practices", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Good Hygiene Practices"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the common Allergens in foods?",
        answers: ["Casein in Milk", "Peanuts", "Eggs", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Which food allergen has the highest  occurrence in the world?",
        answers: ["Tree Nut", "Shellfish", "Soybean", "Peanut"],
        correct: "Peanut"
    },
    {
        question: "Anaphylactic shock is characterized?",
        answers: ["By Gastrointestinal tract, skin,  respiratory tract and  cardiovascular systems", "By local tissue reactions on  the lips, in the mouth and  throat", "By flushing, urticaria, itching", "All of the above"],
        correct: "By Gastrointestinal tract, skin,  respiratory tract and  cardiovascular systems"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Food Toxicity?",
        answers: ["Adverse reaction to food due  to the presence of naturally  occuring toxins in foods", "Adverse reaction to food due  to the presence of  adulterants in foods", "Adverse reaction to food  due to the presence of  contaminants in foods", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Adverse reaction to food due  to the presence of naturally  occuring toxins in foods"
    },
    {
        question: "How many types of certification  programmes are available under FoSTaC?",
        answers: ["10", "15", "17", "20"],
        correct: "17"
    },
    {
        question: "What is Food intolerance?",
        answers: ["Adverse reaction of food in  which body's immune system  is not involved", "Adverse reaction of food in  which body's immune  system is involved", "Adverse reaction of food in  which body's immune  system is involved", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Adverse reaction of food in  which body's immune system  is not involved"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the probable causes of Food  Allergies?",
        answers: ["New proteins introduced into  foods during genetic  manipulation", "Environmental factors", "Lifestyle and eating  behaviours", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What are food allergies?",
        answers: ["An immunologic reaction  resulting from the ingestion,  contact or inhalation of a  food or food additive", "An adverse reaction to a  food in which the body's  immune system is not  involved", "A metabolic food disorder  where food borne  substances interfere with  normal metabolic processes", "All of the above"],
        correct: "An immunologic reaction  resulting from the ingestion,  contact or inhalation of a  food or food additive"
    },
    {
        question: "What does FoSTaC stand for?",
        answers: ["Food Start Ups and certification", "Food safety testing and certification", "Food Safety Training and Certification", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Food Safety Training and Certification"
    },
    { // 40
        question: "What should be implemented by the food businesses to provide assurance of food safety?",
        answers: ["HACCP", "PRP", "FSMS", "GMP"],
        correct: "FSMS"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of QMS?",
        answers: ["Quality Movement System", "Quality Management Safety", "Quality Management System", "Quality Manager for Safety"],
        correct: "Quality Management System"
    },
    {
        question: "Schedule 4 of FSS Licensing Regulations has how many parts?",
        answers: ["4 parts", "5 parts", "6 parts", "7 parts"],
        correct: "5 parts"
    },
    {
        question: "What is FIFO?",
        answers: ["First Information for Organization", "First in First out", "Figure in figure out", "First index First obtained"],
        correct: "First in First out"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of FMEA is?",
        answers: ["False Mode Effect Analysis", "Fast Mode Effective Analysis", "Failure Mode Effect Analysis", "Failure Medium Effect Analysis"],
        correct: "Failure Mode Effect Analysis"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the micronutrients to be added in  milk?",
        answers: ["Vitamin C", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin D", "Both vitamin A and D"],
        correct: "Both vitamin A and D"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the micronutrients to be added in milk?",
        answers: ["Vitamin C", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin D", "Both vitamin A and D"],
        correct: "Both vitamin A and D"
    },
    {
        question: "Staples like rice and wheat are fortified with?",
        answers: ["Iron", "folic acid", "Vitamin B12", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Fats and Oils are fortified with which micronutrients?",
        answers: ["Vitamin A and D", "Vitamin A", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin E"],
        correct: "Vitamin A and D"
    },
    { // 30
        question: "Double fortified salt DFS contains?",
        answers: ["Iron and Folic acid", "Iron and Iodine", "Calcium and Vitamin D", "Iron and Vitamin C"],
        correct: "Iron and Iodine"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of RUCO?",
        answers: ["Repurpose Used Cooking Oil", "Resused Cooking Oil", "Refined Cooking Oil", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Repurpose Used Cooking Oil"
    },
    {
        question: "TFA content should not be more than how much per serving?",
        answers: ["0.1gm", "0.2gm", "0.3gm", "0.4gm"],
        correct: "0.2gm"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the sources of Trans fat?",
        answers: ["HVO", "Vanaspati", "Margarine", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the recommended allowance for salt by WHO for an adult?",
        answers: ["3g per day", "4g per day", "5g per day", "6g per day"],
        correct: "5g per day"
    },
    {
        question: "Food is said to be adulterated when?",
        answers: ["Intentional addition or extraction is done", "Unintentional addition or extraction is done", "Both", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Intentional addition or extraction is done"
    },
    {
        question: "FSSAI has developed a simple, illustrated manual to detect common adulterants at home called?",
        answers: ["ART", "DART", "CART", "TART"],
        correct: "DART"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the purpose of Eat Right Awards?",
        answers: ["If you eat a well balanced diet", "If you serve safe and hygienic foods", "If you have excelled in contributing in the space of safe foods and healthy diets", "If you are a certified  food vendor"],
        correct: "If you have excelled in contributing in the space of safe foods and healthy diets"
    },
    {
        question: "Indians need to be more conscious and mindful of our diets because?",
        answers: ["There is rising incidence of diet-related diseases and  lifestyle disorders", "It incurs huge economic burden", "It imepeds productivity", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "The aim of Swastha Bharat Yatra is?",
        answers: ["Eat Healthy and Eat Safe", "To cascade the message of  Eat Right India to every  corner of the country", "To adopt a healthy life style", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    { // 20
        question: "Eat Right India movement is built on two broad pillars?",
        answers: ["Eat Healthy and Eat Safe", "Eat Right and Eat Safe", "Eat Healthy and Eat  Nutritious", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Eat Healthy and Eat Safe"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the nation wide campaign of FSSAI  to reduce the intake of HFSS foods?",
        answers: ["Thoda sa kam", "Thoda hisaab se", "Aaj se thoda kam", "Thoda sa bus"],
        correct: "Aaj se thoda kam"
    },
    {
        question: "Objectives of IFSA?",
        answers: ["Help minimize food wastage", "prevent food loss along the  supply chain", "Provide strategic policy,  regulatory, and programme  support to food loss and  waste reduction initiatives", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Swasth Bharat Yatra is inspired by?",
        answers: ["Narender Modi", "Ayushaman Bharat", "Mahatma Gandhi", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Mahatma Gandhi"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the Food Hygiene Rating Scheme  of FSSAI for restrauants?",
        answers: ["Serve Safe and Healthy", "Serve Safe", "Serve Safe and Nutritious", "Serve Right"],
        correct: "Serve Safe"
    },
    {
        question: "What is FFRC?",
        answers: ["Food Fortification Resource  Centre", "Food for Resource Centre", "Food Fortified Resource  Centre", "Food Fortification  Centre"],
        correct: "Food Fortification Resource  Centre"
    },
    {
        question: "The purpose of FFRC is to provide?",
        answers: ["Information and technical  assistance on standards of  fortified foods", "Quality assurance and  control for production of  fortified foods", "Assure safe and wholesome  food for all", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the initiative which is used for  training and capacity building of the  street food vendors?",
        answers: ["Project Clean Street Food", "Project Street Food", "Project Clean and Hygienic  Street Food", "Project Street Vendor"],
        correct: "Project Clean Street Food"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of HFSS?",
        answers: ["High Fat, Sugar and Salt", "Highly fried Saturated  Sources", "High Fat, Sodium and  Saccharin", "None of the above"],
        correct: "High Fat, Sugar and Salt"
    },
    {
        question: "Common Adulterants in milk are?",
        answers: ["Non permitted Colours", "Sodium bi carbonate", "Water and starch", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    { // 10
        question: "Name the SNF resource book for home?",
        answers: ["Pink Book", "Green Book", "Orange Book", "Yellow Book"],
        correct: "Pink Book"
    },
    {
        question: "The key purpose of SNF initiatives is to  bring about?",
        answers: ["Social change amongst the  citizens", "Behavioural change amongst  the citizens", "Educate the consumers", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of RUCO?",
        answers: ["Repurpose Used Cooking Oil", "Re used Cooking Oil", "Reduced Cooking Oil", "Resrticted use of  cooking oil"],
        correct: "Repurpose Used Cooking Oil"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of FoSTAC?",
        answers: ["Food Safety Training  Accreditattion and  Certification", "Food Safety Training and  Certification", "Food Safety Training and  Accreditattion", "Food Safety Training"],
        correct: "Food Safety Training and  Certification"
    },
    {
        question: "What are the components of Eat Right Tool Kit?",
        answers: ["Handbook and Tools  for a Frontline health workers", "Engagement Material  for a Citizens", "Both", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Both"
    },
    {
        question: "What does IFSA stands for?",
        answers: ["The Indian Food Sharing  Alliance", "The Indian Food Saving  Alliance", "The Indian Food Security  Alliance", "The Indian Food  Sharing Agency"],
        correct: "The Indian Food Sharing  Alliance"
    },
    {
        question: "Investing in the health of the employee  helps in improving?",
        answers: ["Company's image", "Productivity", "Health and well being", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the DART Book used to detect?",
        answers: ["adulteration", "Contamination", "None of the above", "Both"],
        correct: "adulteration"
    },
    {
        question: "What should be the TPC of oil as per  FSSAI?",
        answers: ["10%", "15%", "20%", "25%"],
        correct: "25%"
    },
    {
        question: "During fever, the basal metabolic rate of  a person?",
        answers: ["Increases", "Is zero", "Decreases", "Remains unaltered"],
        correct: "Increases"
    },
    
]


const eatrightquestionbank3 = [
    // this following set is taken from fssai which made a alexa based eat right quiz
    { // 134
        question: "When potentially hazardous food is  received at an establishment, what  should be the temperature of the food?",
        answers: ["greater than 5\u00B0C", "less than 5\u00B0C", "greater than 0\u00B0C", "less than 0\u00B0C"],
        correct: "less than 5\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "Potable water should be tested according  to which standard?",
        answers: ["IS 10500", "IS 15000", "IS 17650", "IS 22500"],
        correct: "IS 10500"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the best temperature for the  water used to clean utensils in a hotel or  restaurant?",
        answers: ["23 degree C", "33 degree C", "43 degree C", "53 degree C"],
        correct: "43 degree C"
    },
    {
        question: "What should be the level of luminance in  food preparation areas in a hotel or  restaurant?",
        answers: ["200 lux", "300 lux", "400 lux", "500 lux"],
        correct: "500 lux"
    },
    { // 130
        question: "In a food service establishment ideally  one tap for hand washing is  recommended for how many food  handlers?",
        answers: ["15-20", "25-30", "35-40", "45-50"],
        correct: "15-20"
    },
    {
        question: "How much humidity is desirable to  ensure safety in areas where food is  being handled in a food service  establishment?",
        answers: ["More than 80\u00B0C", "Less than 80\u00B0C", "More than 65\u00B0C", "Less than 65\u00B0C"],
        correct: "Less than 65\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "Cooked rice is most likely to get  contaminated with which pathogenic  bacteria?",
        answers: ["Clostridium botulinum", "Campylobacter jejuni", "Bacillus cereus", "Salmonella SPP"],
        correct: "Bacillus cereus"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is not a disease caused by protozoa?",
        answers: ["Giardiasis", "Amoebiasis", "Cryptosporidiosis", "Poliomyelitis"],
        correct: "Poliomyelitis"
    },
    {
        question: "What kind of infectious agents are Prions  which caused the mad cow disease?",
        answers: ["Bacteria", "Virus", "Pathogenic protein", "Protozoa"],
        correct: "Pathogenic protein"
    },
    {
        question: "Which preservative can on heat  processing form nitrosamines in  processed meats?",
        answers: ["Benzoates", "Nitrites", "Sulphites", "Sorbates"],
        correct: "Nitrites"
    },
    {
        question: "Which preservative can on heat  processing form nitrosamines in  processed meats?",
        answers: ["Benzoates", "Nitrites", "Sulphites", "Sorbates"],
        correct: "Nitrites"
    },
    {
        question: "For which artificial sweetener does the  label say that it is not for  phenylketonurics?",
        answers: ["Aspartame", "Sucralose", "Acesulfame", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Aspartame"
    },
    {
        question: "Which committee of FAO or WHO  evaluates the hazards posed by different  food additives?",
        answers: ["JECFA", "JMPR", "CCCF", "CCFL"],
        correct: "JECFA"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the term used for the amount of  a food additive which can be ingested  daily over a lifetime without appreciable  health risk?",
        answers: ["RDA", "ADI", "MPL", "FDA"],
        correct: "ADI"
    },
    { // 120
        question: "Which of these substances, naturally  present in plant foods, inhibits the  uptake of iodine by the thyroid gland?",
        answers: ["Phytate", "Oxalate", "Goitrogen", "Tannin"],
        correct: "Goitrogen"
    },
    {
        question: "Arsenic poisoning causes which of the  following symptoms?",
        answers: ["Garlic breath", "Nerve damage", "Skin lesions", "All the above"],
        correct: "All the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Itai-Itai disease outbreak in Japan was  attributed to which heavy metal  poisoning?",
        answers: ["Lead", "Cadmium", "Copper", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Cadmium"
    },
    {
        question: "Minamata disease outbreak in Japan was  attributed to which heavy metal  poisoning?",
        answers: ["Lead", "Cadmium", "Copper", "Mercury"],
        correct: "Mercury"
    },
    {
        question: "Consumption of mustard oil which has  been adulterated with argemone oil can  lead to what kind of disease condition?",
        answers: ["Gastroenteritis", "Epidemic dropsy", "Cyanosis", "Seizures"],
        correct: "Epidemic dropsy"
    },
    {
        question: "Which mold produces the mycotoxin  called Aflatoxin?",
        answers: ["Aspergillus SPP", "Claviceps SPP", "Fusarium SPP", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Aspergillus SPP"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these viruses is responsible for  gastroenteritis and diarrhoea?",
        answers: ["Adenovirus", "Norwalk virus", "Rotavirus", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is the bacterium responsible for  what is referred to as Traveller's  diarrhoea?",
        answers: ["E-coli", "Salmonella", "Clostridium", "Staphylococcus"],
        correct: "E-coli"
    },
    {
        question: "Foods which are acidic in pH are usually  spoilt by which kind of microbes?",
        answers: ["Bacteria", "Virus", "Yeasts and Molds", "Protozoa"],
        correct: "Yeasts and Molds"
    },
    {
        question: "Bacteria which are able to grow at low  temperatures are called?",
        answers: ["Psychrophiles", "Mesophiles", "Thermophiles", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Psychrophiles"
    },
    { // 110
        question: "The multiplication of bacteria is  maximum in which phase of the growth  curve of the bacteria?",
        answers: ["Lag phase", "Log phase", "Stationary phase", "Death phase"],
        correct: "Log phase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which toxin is present in the Pufferfish?",
        answers: ["Dioxin", "Tetrodotoxin", "Ciguatera", "Histamine"],
        correct: "Tetrodotoxin"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is an anti-metal  decreasing the absorption of metals in  our body?",
        answers: ["Citrate", "Sorbate", "Phytate", "Fumarate"],
        correct: "Phytate"
    },
    {
        question: "When starch based foods are cooked at  high temperatures, which harmful  chemical is produced?",
        answers: ["AGE's", "Heterocyclic amines", "Acrylamide", "Nitrosamines"],
        correct: "Acrylamide"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is not an anti-nutritional factor present in food?",
        answers: ["Phytate", "Oxalate", "Tannin", "Shellfish toxin"],
        correct: "Shellfish toxin"
    },
    {
        question: "Bacteria which are round in shape are called?",
        answers: ["Bacilli", "Vibrio", "Cocci", "Spirochete"],
        correct: "Cocci"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is not a disease caused by  bacteria?",
        answers: ["Amoebiasis", "Typhoid", "Shigellosis", "Cholera"],
        correct: "Amoebiasis"
    },
    {
        question: "Which group of bacteria if detected in  food indicate that the food has been  contaminated by faeces?",
        answers: ["Bifidobacter", "Staphylococcus", "Coliforms", "Lactobacillus"],
        correct: "Coliforms"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of BPA, a chemical  present in plastics?",
        answers: ["Butylene A", "Bisphenol A", "B Phenylalanine", "B paraffin"],
        correct: "Bisphenol A"
    },
    {
        question: "Which toxic chemical is present in the green portions of potatoes?",
        answers: ["Solanine", "Starch", "Chlorophyll", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Solanine"
    },
    { // 100
        question: "Which of these food- borne illnesses is not caused by bacteria?",
        answers: ["Cholera", "Typhoid", "Botulism", "Hepatitis A"],
        correct: "Typhoid"
    },
    {
        question: "Which dangerous bacteria may be present in raw eggs?",
        answers: ["Bacillus", "Salmonella", "Streptococcus", "Lactobacillus"],
        correct: "Salmonella"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the danger zone of temperature at which foods should not be stored?",
        answers: ["10-80\u00B0C", "20-100\u00B0C", "0-30\u00B0C", "5-60\u00B0C"],
        correct: "5-60\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "How much is the TSS of tomato sauce?",
        answers: ["40 %", "15 %", "25 %", "35 %"],
        correct: "25 %"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the Antinutritional factor in cotton seed?",
        answers: ["Tannin", "Trypsin inhibitor", "Gossypol", "Saponins"],
        correct: "Gossypol"
    },
    {
        question: "Nitrates are used in food as?",
        answers: ["Leavening agent", "Anticaking agent", "Curing agent", "Antimicrobial agent"],
        correct: "Curing agent"
    },
    {
        question: "The principal flavouring agent of mint is?",
        answers: ["Eugenol", "Methanol", "Menthol", "Vanilla"],
        correct: "Menthol"
    },
    {
        question: "Carmoisine is a food additive used as a?",
        answers: ["Liquifing agent", "Moisturising agent", "Flavour", "Colour"],
        correct: "Colour"
    },
    {
        question: "Which enzyme leads to browning of apple?",
        answers: ["Polyphenol oxidase", "Lipase", "Catalase", "Superoxidase"],
        correct: "Polyphenol oxidase"
    },
    {
        question: "Which enzyme is denatured at blanching temperature?",
        answers: ["Peroxidase", "Catalase", "Oxidase", "Lipase"],
        correct: "Peroxidase"
    },
    { // 90
        question: "What is liquid Nitrogen?",
        answers: ["Gas", "Vapour", "Cryogenic Fluid", "Fluid"],
        correct: "Cryogenic Fluid"
    },
    {
        question: "Method used to remove hydratable gums  in soyabean oil is known as?",
        answers: ["Desolvation", "Alkalisation", "Degumming", "Dehydration"],
        correct: "Degumming"
    },
    {
        question: "Moisture retention agents are termed as?",
        answers: ["Moisture scavenger", "Humectant", "Dehumidifier", "Retentator"],
        correct: "Humectant"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the unit operation for thermal  food preservation?",
        answers: ["Irradiation", "High pressure processing", "Blanching", "Pulsed Electric Field"],
        correct: "Blanching"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the process for removing moisture from frozen food?",
        answers: ["Tray drying", "Puff drying", "Freeze drying", "Spray drying"],
        correct: "Freeze drying"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of HoSU?",
        answers: ["History of Safe Use", "Heat of Safe Use", "History of Standard Use", "None of the above"],
        correct: "History of Safe Use"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is a Cryogenic  Fluid?",
        answers: ["Liquid Nitrogen N2", "Ammonia", "Oxygen", "Bromine"],
        correct: "Liquid Nitrogen N2"
    },
    {
        question: "An example of a bleaching agent?",
        answers: ["Silver nitrite", "Potassium sulphate", "Sodium hypochlorite", "Calcium sulphate"],
        correct: "Sodium hypochlorite"
    },
    {
        question: "Change that a lipid undergoes leading to  undesirable flavour and odour is known  as?",
        answers: ["Gelatinisation", "Turbidity", "Gelation", "Rancidity"],
        correct: "Rancidity"
    },
    {
        question: "Sterilization by high pressure steam at 121\u00B0C for 15-20 minutes is called?",
        answers: ["Pasteurisation", "Irradiation", "Blanching", "Autoclaving"],
        correct: "Autoclaving"
    },
    { // 80
        question: "Substances used to preserve foods by  lowering pH are?",
        answers: ["Baking powder and soda", "Smoke and dry ice", "Vinegar and citric acid", "Salt and sugar"],
        correct: "Vinegar and citric acid"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the unit of radiation energy?",
        answers: ["Roentgen", "Gray (Gy)", "Sievert", "Radiation absorbed dose (rad)"],
        correct: "Gray (Gy)"
    },
    {
        question: "Product produced by hydrolysis of  Sucrose in presence of Invertase?",
        answers: ["Glucose", "Fructose", "Invert Sugar", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Invert Sugar"
    },
    {
        question: "The system of altering gas composition  for storage of fruits is called?",
        answers: ["Calculated Atmospheric  Storage", "Modified Atmospheric  Storage", "Controlled Atmospheric  Storage", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Modified Atmospheric  Storage"
    },
    {
        question: "Salt or Sugar is added to foods for longer shelf life as they?",
        answers: ["Create acidic medium", "Bind to water", "Kill microorganisms", "Dissolve the cell walls"],
        correct: "Bind to water"
    },
    {
        question: "Crystallization for long time leads to  which size of crystals?",
        answers: ["Small", "Large", "No crystals formed", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Large"
    },
    {
        question: "What is pheromone trap used for?",
        answers: ["Trapping animals", "Trapping insects", "Trapping birds", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Trapping insects"
    },
    {
        question: "How many feet above the ground should fly light traps be mounted?",
        answers: ["1 to 3 feet", "10 to 15 feet", "4 to 6 feet", "8 to 10 feet"],
        correct: "4 to 6 feet"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is incorrect?",
        answers: ["Antiseptic - used on living  tissues and cells to destroy  infections", "Disinfectants - to destroy  microorganisms that infect  non-living objects", "Sanitizers - used to reduce  microbes for human safety.", "They play the same  role"],
        correct: "They play the same  role"
    },
    {
        question: "Which is a flour bleaching agent?",
        answers: ["Calcium peroxide", "Nitrogen dioxide", "Chlorine", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    { // 70
        question: "Thermo processing done at high pressure  is called?",
        answers: ["Pasteurization", "Sterilization", "Retortable packaging", "Aseptic process"],
        correct: "Retortable packaging"
    },
    {
        question: "Full form of CCP is?",
        answers: ["Cost Control Program", "Configuration control panel", "Critical control point", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Critical control point"
    },
    {
        question: "Additives that help in maintaining pH are called?",
        answers: ["Buffering agent", "Acid", "Base", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Buffering agent"
    },
    {
        question: "What is made by churning pasteurized cream?",
        answers: ["Milk", "Ice cream", "Yogurt", "Butter"],
        correct: "Butter"
    },
    {
        question: "Foods sterilized by irradiation can be  stored for how long without  refrigeration?",
        answers: ["Weeks", "Months", "Years", "Days"],
        correct: "Years"
    },
    {
        question: "Irradiation causes undesirable flavour changes in which products?",
        answers: ["Dairy", "Grain", "Meat", "Vegetable"],
        correct: "Dairy"
    },
    {
        question: "What can inactivate enzymes?",
        answers: ["Radiation", "Cooling", "Drying", "Freezing"],
        correct: "Radiation"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the temperature in a dry store?",
        answers: ["11-18\u00B0C", "0-4\u00B0C", "8-10\u00B0C", "20-25\u00B0C"],
        correct: "11-18\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "Where should meat be stored in the  refrigerator?",
        answers: ["Freezer", "Bottom shelf", "Middle shelf", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Bottom shelf"
    },
    {
        question: "Gas used to package freeze dried foods?",
        answers: ["Oxygen", "Nitrogen", "Hydrogen", "Carbon dioxide"],
        correct: "Nitrogen"
    },
    { // 60
        question: "Main raw produce for production of beer is?",
        answers: ["Hops", "Yeast", "Malted barley", "Water"],
        correct: "Malted barley"
    },
    {
        question: "Name the alkaloid toxicant in Potato?",
        answers: ["Piperine", "Cocaine", "Capsaicin", "Solainin"],
        correct: "Solainin"
    },
    {
        question: "Method of roasting and cooking in a tightly closed pan is called?",
        answers: ["Roasting", "Frying", "Braising", "Smoking"],
        correct: "Braising"
    },
    {
        question: "Incidence of foodborne illness is at its highest in which season?",
        answers: ["Winter", "Monsoon", "Spring", "Summer"],
        correct: "Summer"
    },
    {
        question: "Which device is used to detect the odour and flavour of food?",
        answers: ["Electronic nose", "E-tongue", "Texture analyse", "GC"],
        correct: "Electronic nose"
    },
    {
        question: "The only inorganic acid used as a food acidulate is?",
        answers: ["Succinic acid ", "Tartaric acid", "Nitric acid", "Phosphoric acid"],
        correct: "Phosphoric acid"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is not a chemical  leavening agent?",
        answers: ["Baking Soda", "Sodium tartrate", "Ammonium Carbonate", "Yeast"],
        correct: "Sodium tartrate"
    },
    {
        question: "Treatment of fruits and vegetables with  boiling water or steam followed by  cooling is called?",
        answers: ["Lye peeling", "Lye dipping", "Blanching", "Peeling"],
        correct: "Blanching"
    },
    {
        question: "Total heating time required to accomplish complete destruction of spores is called?",
        answers: ["Thermal Death Time", "Pasteurization", "Sterilization", "Aseptic process"],
        correct: "Thermal Death Time"
    },
    {
        question: "Blanching is done to preserve colour of fruits and vegetables?",
        answers: ["Preserves colour", "Inactivates enzyme", "Preserves flavour", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    { // 50
        question: "At what temperature should you keep your refrigerator?",
        answers: ["5-10\u00B0C", "10-20\u00B0C", "0-5\u00B0C", "-5-0\u00B0C"],
        correct: "0-5\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "At low temperatures, the rate of  respiration of harvested fruits decreases  or increase?",
        answers: ["Decreases", "Increases", "Remains same", "All of the above"],
        correct: "Decreases"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the expensive method of drying to preserve foods?",
        answers: ["Solar drying ", "Freeze drying", "Tray drying", "Drum drying"],
        correct: "Freeze drying"
    },
    {
        question: "Method used to remove hydratable gums in soyabean oil is called?",
        answers: ["Washing", "Peeling", "Water Degumming or Degumming", "Cleaning"],
        correct: "Water Degumming or Degumming"
    },
    {
        question: "Moisture retention agents are termed as?",
        answers: ["Surfactant", "Humectant", "Emulsifier", "Stabilizer"],
        correct: "Humectant"
    },
    {
        question: "SOP stands for?",
        answers: ["Standard Operational Procedure", "Sufficient Operational Part", "Standard Operating Procedure", "Sufficient Operating Point"],
        correct: "Standard Operating Procedure"
    },
    {
        question: "Packaging that increases shelf life of milk is?",
        answers: ["Aseptic", "Tetrapack", "Multilayer film", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Time-Temperature combination for HTST treatment of milk is?",
        answers: ["72\u00B0C for 15 seconds", "82\u00B0C for 15 seconds", "63\u00B0C for 15 min", "135\u00B0C for 1 second"],
        correct: "72\u00B0C for 15 seconds"
    },
    {
        question: "Receiving temperature of chilled food should be at or below?",
        answers: ["0\u00B0C", "5\u00B0C", "10\u00B0C", "-18\u00B0C"],
        correct: "5\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these is a leavening agent?",
        answers: ["Sodium carbonate", "Sodium chloride", "Sodium bicarbonate", "Sodium hydroxide"],
        correct: "Sodium bicarbonate"
    },
    { // 40
        question: "How do salt and sugar help to increase  shelf life?",
        answers: ["Create acidic medium", "Bind to water", "Kill microorganisms", "Dissolve the cell walls"],
        correct: "Bind to water"
    },
    {
        question: "Tocopherol is used in foods as?",
        answers: ["Acidity regulator", "Stabilizer", "Antioxidant", "Emulsifier"],
        correct: "Antioxidant"
    },
    {
        question: "Packaging of food in sterile packaging  material is called as?",
        answers: ["Sterile packaging", "Aseptic packaging", "Septic packaging", "Fertile packaging"],
        correct: "Aseptic packaging"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the use of Sodium bicarbonate?",
        answers: ["Humectant", "Preservative", "Leavening agent", "Stabilizing And Emulsifying agent"],
        correct: "Leavening agent"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the full form of CCP?",
        answers: ["Critical Count Point", "Crisis Control Point", "Crisis Count Point", "Critical Control Point"],
        correct: "Critical Control Point"
    },
    {
        question: "GAP stands for?",
        answers: ["Good Action Plan", "Good Action Practices", "Good Agriculture Practices", "Good Awareness Programme"],
        correct: "Good Agriculture Practices"
    },
    {
        question: "Thermo processing done at high pressure is called?",
        answers: ["Retort Packaging", "Blanching", "High Pressure processing", "Pulse electric field"],
        correct: "Retort Packaging"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the process of moisture  adjustment in wheat?",
        answers: ["Cleaning", "Conditioning", "Separation of endosperm", "Flour formation"],
        correct: "Conditioning"
    },
    {
        question: "Which method is used for altering  environmental conditions in which  spoilage microorganisms are unable to  grow in the food?",
        answers: ["Preservation", "Fortification", "Sterilization", "Sanitation"],
        correct: "Preservation"
    },
    {
        question: "Which term is applied to all stomach and  intestinal disturbances due to food  contaminated with certain  microorganisms or to their toxins?",
        answers: ["Food allergy ", "Food poisoning", "Food infection", "Food spoilage"],
        correct: "Food poisoning"
    },
    { // 30
        question: "The transfer of harmful micro-organisms  from one item of food to another via a  non-food surface such as human hands,  equipment, or utensils is known as?",
        answers: ["Contamination", "Spoilage", "Cross-contamination", "Poisoning"],
        correct: "Cross-contamination"
    },
    {
        question: "The term used to indicate water which is free from pathogenic bacteria and palatable?",
        answers: ["Potable water", "Sterile water", "Hygienic water", "Palatable water"],
        correct: "Potable water"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the importance of freezing  foods?",
        answers: ["To kill bacteria", "To cease multiplying bacteria", "Preserving vitamins", "To kill virus"],
        correct: "To cease multiplying bacteria"
    },
    {
        question: "What happens to the can of canned foods at high altitudes?",
        answers: ["Contract", "Expand", "No change", "Bacteria are destroyed"],
        correct: "Expand"
    },
    {
        question: "The danger zone in the food preparation  refers to temperature between?",
        answers: ["0-40\u00B0F", "40-140\u00B0F", "140- 180\u00B0F", "Above 180\u00B0F"],
        correct: "40-140\u00B0F"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the minimum temperature at  which food should be held during  pasteurisation?",
        answers: ["15°C", "25°C", "63°C", "55°C"],
        correct: "63°C"
    },
    {
        question: "Technology of processing of frozen peas is called?",
        answers: ["Freeze drying", "IQF, Individual Quick Freezing", "Freezing", "Coating"],
        correct: "IQF, Individual Quick Freezing"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the time-temperature  combination to treat milk at high  temperature short time?",
        answers: ["63\u00B0C, 145\u00B0F for 30 minutes", "72\u00B0C, 161\u00B0F for 15 seconds", "89\u00B0C, 191\u00B0F for 1 second", "90\u00B0C, 194\u00B0F for 0.5  seconds"],
        correct: "72\u00B0C, 161\u00B0F for 15 seconds"
    },
    {
        question: "Frozen meat should be defrosted in the?",
        answers: ["Open", "On fire", "Refrigerator", "Should be directly cooked"],
        correct: "Refrigerator"
    },
    {
        question: "Another term for cold sterilization is?",
        answers: ["Pasteurisation", "Irradiation", "Freezing", "Blanching"],
        correct: "Irradiation"
    },
    { // 20
        question: "Handling foods after using toilet may lead  to?",
        answers: ["Sterilisation", "Cleaning", "Cross-contamination", "Depletion of nutrients"],
        correct: "Cross-contamination"
    },
    {
        question: "Symbol for irradiated foods is called?",
        answers: ["Agmark", "Silk Mark", "Radura", "Gamma"],
        correct: "Radura"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of the following is correct?",
        answers: ["Hurdle technology is a multi  target preservation", "Hurdle technology is process  to eliminate or control  pathogens", "Hurdle technology combines  non-thermal food processing  with traditional or other  emerging technologies", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    {
        question: "Chopping board used for handling raw  vegetables and raw meat should be?",
        answers: ["Same", "Separate", "Old worn out", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Separate"
    },
    {
        question: "SOP stands for?",
        answers: ["Standard Operating  Procedure", "Small outline package", "Standard of practice", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Standard Operating  Procedure"
    },
    {
        question: "Cutting boards must be sanitized with?",
        answers: ["Chemical sanitizer", "Chlorine bleach", "Detergent", "None of the above"],
        correct: "Chlorine bleach"
    },
    {
        question: "Receiving temperature of chilled food should be at or below?",
        answers: ["7\u00B0C", "5\u00B0C", "3\u00B0C", "6\u00B0C"],
        correct: "5\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "HTST with respect to pasteurization is?",
        answers: ["High temperature short time  treatment", "High Temperature Short  Time", "High temperature storage  test", "None of the above"],
        correct: "High Temperature Short  Time"
    },
    {
        question: "Curing is commonly used for the  preservation of?",
        answers: ["Vegetables", "Meat and Fish", "Cereals and Pulses", "Fruits"],
        correct: "Meat and Fish"
    },
    {
        question: "Pasteurization is done to kill?",
        answers: ["Selective microorganisms", "All microorganisms", "Yeast", "Yeast and its spores"],
        correct: "Selective microorganisms"
    },
    { // 10
        question: "At low temperature, rate of respiration of harvested fruits?",
        answers: ["Increases", "Decreases", "Remains same", "Stops"],
        correct: "Decreases"
    },
    {
        question: "At what temperature should you keep  frozen food?",
        answers: ["4\u00B0C", "0\u00B0C", "-18\u00B0C", "10\u00B0C"],
        correct: "-18\u00B0C"
    },
    {
        question: "Who developed the canning process?",
        answers: ["Nicholas Appert", "Nicholas Flemming", "Charles Darwin", "Blaise Pascal"],
        correct: "Nicholas Appert"
    },
    {
        question: "Elimination of all forms of bacteria is  called?",
        answers: ["Pasteurisation", "Sterilization", "Blanching", "Appertization"],
        correct: "Sterilization"
    },
    {
        question: "What help in maintaining pH?",
        answers: ["Buffering agents", "Sequestrants", "Anti-caking agents", "Anti-foaming agents"],
        correct: "Buffering agents"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the primary purpose of blanching  food?",
        answers: ["Clean the food", "Prevent pest infestation", "Inactivate enzymes in food", "Prevent food from drying"],
        correct: "Inactivate enzymes in food"
    },
    {
        question: "What is added to fruits before freezing  commercially to protect quality?",
        answers: ["Vitamin E", "Ascorbic acid", "Water", "Sugar"],
        correct: "Ascorbic acid"
    },
    {
        question: "What is a substitute for proper hand  washing?",
        answers: ["Hand Sanitizers", "Gloves", "Tongs", "None"],
        correct: "None"
    },
    {
        question: "How long you should scrub your hand?",
        answers: ["5 seconds", "10 seconds", "15 seconds", "20 seconds"],
        correct: "20 seconds"
    },
    {
        question: "Which of these helps in pest control?",
        answers: ["Covered drains", "Food containers with tight  lids", "Avoid food spillage", "All of the above"],
        correct: "All of the above"
    },
    
]



const eatrightquestionbank4 = [
        // this following set is taken from fssai which made a alexa based eat right quiz
        { // 192
            question: "Which reagent is used to detect presence  of starch in milk/ milk products?",
            answers: ["Iodine solution", "Sulphuric acid", "Alcohol", "Hydrochloric acid"],
            correct: "Iodine solution"
        },
        {
            question: "Action to eliminate the cause of a  potential nonconformity.",
            answers: ["Corrective action", "Preventive action", "Correction", "None of these"],
            correct: "Preventive action"
        },
        { // 190
            question: "Action to eliminate the cause of a  detected nonconformity",
            answers: ["Corrective action", "Preventive action", "Correction", "None of these"],
            correct: "Corrective action"
        },
        {
            question: "Mandatory standard for the sale of food  products to fulfill in India",
            answers: ["BIS", "APEDA", "DADF", "FSS Act"],
            correct: "FSS Act"
        },
        {
            question: "Mid day meal scheme covers under?",
            answers: ["BIS", "FSS Act", "APEDA", "EIC"],
            correct: "FSS Act"
        },
        {
            question: "BIS, AOAC, APHA testing standards are?",
            answers: ["Reference methods", "In house methods", "Non validated methods", "Secondary methods"],
            correct: "Reference methods"
        },
        {
            question: "In relation to FBO, In house laboratory  means?",
            answers: ["FBO own laboratory", "Consumer laboratory", "Independent third party", "All of these"],
            correct: "FBO own laboratory"
        },
        {
            question: "Full Cream Milk contains?",
            answers: ["3% fat", "6 % fat", "4.5 % fat", "1.5 % fat"],
            correct: "6 % fat"
        },
        {
            question: "FBOs can apply for license through?",
            answers: ["Online mode", "Hard copy to authority", "Both", "Not required license to  start business"],
            correct: "Both"
        },
        {
            question: "Microscopic organism is?",
            answers: ["Earthworm", "Yeast", "Flatworms", "Tape worms"],
            correct: "Yeast"
        },
        {
            question: "LCMS-MS used for analysis of?",
            answers: ["Antibiotics", "Pesticide", "Both", "None of these"],
            correct: "Both"
        },
        {
            question: "Pesticides are causative agent of?",
            answers: ["Goiter", "Diabetes", "TB", "Cancer"],
            correct: "Cancer"
        },
        { // 180
            question: "Drug resistances many are induce by  consuming food mainly containing high?",
            answers: ["Antibiotics", "Pesticide", "Heavy metals", "None of these"],
            correct: "Antibiotics"
        },
        {
            question: "India has lifted ban from import of milk  products from china on?",
            answers: ["15th August, 2011", "26th January.2011", "02nd October 2011", "Yet not lifted"],
            correct: "Yet not lifted"
        },
        {
            question: "what means any substance not  intentionally added to food, but which  gets added to articles of food in the  process of their production manufacture,  processing, preparation, treatment,  packing, packaging transport or holding  of articles of such food as a result of  environmental contamination?",
            answers: ["Storage contaminants", "Production contaminants", "Crop contaminant", "Quality contaminants"],
            correct: "Crop contaminant"
        },
        {
            question: "What shall be declared on every package of food?",
            answers: ["Gross quantity", "Net quantity", "Approximate quantity", "None of these"],
            correct: "Net quantity"
        },
        {
            question: "Recommended daily intakes of a nutrient  for healthy people called?",
            answers: ["RDAs", "BMR", "Daily dose", "None of these"],
            correct: "RDAs"
        },
        {
            question: "energy value is calculated in?",
            answers: ["Joule", "Kcal", "Pascal", "Ohm"],
            correct: "Kcal"
        },
        {
            question: "Nutritional Information or nutritional  facts per 100 gm or 100 ml or per serving  of the product shall be given on the label  containing the following?",
            answers: ["Energy", "Fat", "Carbohydrate", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Baudouin test used to check adulteration  of?",
            answers: ["Honey", "Ghee", "Egg products", "Meat products"],
            correct: "Ghee"
        },
        {
            question: "Containers made of plastic materials  should conform to the Indian Standards  Specification, used as appliances or  receptacles for packing or storing  whether partly or wholly, food articles  namely?",
            answers: ["IS : 10146 (Specification for  Polyethylene in contact with  foodstuffs)", "IS : 10142 (Specification for  Styrene Polymers in contact  with foodstuffs", "IS : 10151 (Specification for  Polyvinyl Chloride (PVC), in  contact with foodstuffs)", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "A utensil or container made of the  following materials or metals, when used  in the preparation, packaging and storing  of food shall be deemed to render it unfit  for human consumption?",
            answers: ["Containers which are rusty", "Enameled containers which  have become chipped and  rusty", "Copper or brass containers  which are not properly  tinned", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        { // 170
            question: "Butyrorefractrometer reading indicate?",
            answers: ["Fat adulteration", "Melamine adulteration", "Aflatoxin adulteration", "Histamine adulteration"],
            correct: "Fat adulteration"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the product obtained by  partial removal of water from milk?",
            answers: ["Curd", "Lassi", "Ghee", "Milk Powder"],
            correct: "Milk Powder"
        },
        {
            question: "Evaporated skimmed contain (m/m)?",
            answers: ["Fat content not more than  1.0 percent", "Protein Not less than 34.0  percent", "Both", "None of these"],
            correct: "Both"
        },
        {
            question: "Dahi or curd is a?",
            answers: ["Sterilized Fermented product", "Sterilized coagulated product", "Fermented product", "Cheesy product"],
            correct: "Fermented product"
        },
        {
            question: "what means oils produced from oilcakes  or oilseeds or oil-bearing materials of  plant origin and containing glycerides?",
            answers: ["Vegetable oils", "Milk fat", "Animal fat", "Fish oil"],
            correct: "Vegetable oils"
        },
        {
            question: "what terms shall be taken to refer to the  process of heating every particle of milk  to at least 71.5\u00B0C and holding at such  temperature continuously for at least 15  seconds?",
            answers: ["Hydrogenation", "Coagulation", "Transmission", "Pasteurization"],
            correct: "Pasteurization"
        },
        {
            question: "Total urea content in the milk sample  found 100 ppm on analysis?",
            answers: ["Sample is adulterated and  unsafe", "Sample is adulterated but  safe", "Sample is not adulterated", "Sample is marginally  adulterated"],
            correct: "Sample is not adulterated"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the process of addition of  hydrogen to an edible vegetable oil using  a catalyst to produce a fat with semi-solid  consistency?",
            answers: ["Hydrogenation", "Coagulation", "Transmission", "Pasteurization"],
            correct: "Hydrogenation"
        },
        {
            question: "Why possibility of failure of QC sample is  more compared to quality assurance  (QA)?",
            answers: ["QC is sample based approach  and possibility of any  production failure at any  stage remains high to get  unnoticed.", "QC requires statically  sampling which may be large  for large lots and this is  difficult to follow at  commercial industries.", "QA is the system based  approach and it includes all  component like  procurement, production,  distribution and testing and  every individual has role to  ensure quality", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Consumer purchased packed food and  after opening he found it contains white  cottony structure on surface. What are  these structures may be?",
            answers: ["Bacteria", "Mold", "Protein globules", "None of these"],
            correct: "Mold"
        },
        { // 160
            question: "Food sample tested at plant for colifom  count was found within limit but when  samples taken from market and tested  for colifom count were found very high.  What could be the reason for this?",
            answers: ["1. It is not possible", "2. Because of associated  variations in analysis,  sampling or non  representative sample and  sample attribute.", "3. Storage temperature not  maintain in supply chain", "Both 2 and 3"],
            correct: "Both 2 and 3"
        },
        {
            question: "A consumer sent two packet of food  sample in two different laboratories but  he got different results. What could be  the best technical reason for this?",
            answers: ["It is not possible", "Laboratory may be fraud", "Because of associated  variations in analysis,  sampling or non  representative sample and  sample attribute.", "None of these"],
            correct: "Because of associated  variations in analysis,  sampling or non  representative sample and  sample attribute."
        },
        {
            question: "What is NABL?",
            answers: ["Authority to grant laboratory  accreditation as per ISO  17025.", "Authority to grant BIS  symbol", "Authority to grant food  license", "Authority to grant  MMPO"],
            correct: "Authority to grant BIS  symbol"
        },
        {
            question: "A dairy plant located at one premises  means?",
            answers: ["Considered as single unit", "Considered as multiple unit if  manufacturing many  products", "Considered as multiple unit  because it has different  section, Production,  distribution, procurement in  same unit", "All of these"],
            correct: "Considered as single unit"
        },
        {
            question: "In dairy manufacturing unit what  qualification usually plant  incharge/incharge of technical operation  must have?",
            answers: ["Graduate in electronic  engineering", "Graduate in law", "Graduate in account", "Graduate in dairy and  allied subject"],
            correct: "Graduate in dairy and  allied subject"
        },
        {
            question: "Among the following FBO, which one  requires only registration?",
            answers: ["Small Ice cream stall  operating in local area", "Export unit", "FBO operating in 2 states", "SMP Manufacturer of  10 MT kg"],
            correct: "Small Ice cream stall  operating in local area"
        },
        {
            question: "what means Designated Officers  appointed under Section 36(1) of the Act  by the Food Safety Commissioner of a  State or UT?",
            answers: ["FSO", "CEO", "State Licensing Authority", "State advocate"],
            correct: "State Licensing Authority"
        },
        {
            question: "Schedule - 4 specified?",
            answers: ["General Hygienic and Sanitary  practices", "Product specification", "Testing methods", "Microbial requirement"],
            correct: "General Hygienic and Sanitary  practices"
        },
        {
            question: "Sanitary and hygienic requirements for  food manufacturer or processor or  handler?",
            answers: ["All equipments shall be  placed well away from the  walls to allow proper  inspection.", "There should be efficient  drainage system and there  shall be adequate provisions  for disposal of refuse", "The workers working in  processing and preparation  shall use clean aprons, hand  gloves, and head wears", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Sanitary and hygienic requirements for  street food vendors and units other than  manufacturing or processing?",
            answers: ["Vegetarian and non-vegetarian items should be  segregated", "Potential sources of  contamination like rubbish,  waste water, toilet facilities,  open drains and stray  animals shall be avoided", "Eating, chewing, smoking,  spitting and nose blowing  shall be prohibited within  the premises.", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        { // 150
            question: "Water required in manufacturing of  product shall be?",
            answers: ["Portable", "Industrial grade", "Food grade", "Medical grade"],
            correct: "Portable"
        },
        {
            question: "What maintain sanitary and hygienic  standards and worker's Hygiene to the  category of food business?",
            answers: ["FBO", "DO", "FSO", "Food Analyst"],
            correct: "FBO"
        },
        {
            question: "License may cancel if?",
            answers: ["Display a true copy of the  license granted in Form C  shall at all time at a  prominent place in the  premises.", "Give necessary access to  Licensing Authorities or their  authorized personnel to the  premises", "Inform Authorities about any  change or modifications in  activities /content of license.", "None of these"],
            correct: "None of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Registration is required if?",
            answers: ["Production capacity of food  (other than milk and milk  products and meat and meat  products) does not exceed  100 kg/ltr per day", "Procurement or handling and  collection of milk is up to 500  litres of milk per day", "Slaughtering capacity is 2  large animals or 10 small  animals or 50 poultry birds  per day or less", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Central License required if?",
            answers: ["Food Business Operator  operating in two or more  states", "100 % Export Oriented Units", "Processing units equipped to  handle or process more than  500 kg of meat per day or  150 MT per annum", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Petty Food Manufacturer means any  food manufacturer, who?",
            answers: ["Production capacity of food  (other than milk and milk  products and meat and meat  products) does not exceed  100 kg/ltr per day", "procurement or handling and  collection of milk is up to 500  litres of milk per day", "Slaughtering capacity is 2  large animals or 10 small  animals or 50 poultry birds  per day or less", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "What means the Designated Officer  appointed under section 36 (i) of the Act  by the Commissioner of Food Safety of  the state or by the Chief Executive Officer  of the Food Safety and Standards  Authority of India in his capacity of Food  Safety Commissioner?",
            answers: ["Licensing Authority", "FSO", "Food Analyst", "CEO"],
            correct: "Licensing Authority"
        },
        {
            question: "On the packages/labels of Infant food  which one of the following declaration is  not permitted ?",
            answers: ["Mother's milk is the best for your baby", "Feeding Chart with scope of  feeding", "To be taken under advice of  a medical advice", "Picture of a baby or  mother or both"],
            correct: "Picture of a baby or  mother or both"
        },
        {
            question: "Spice Board has the provision of quality  evaluation services under following  schemes?",
            answers: ["Technology upgradation", "Quality upgradation", "Research and product  development", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "MPEDA offers assistance (including  financial assistance) to marine industry  under plan schemes implemented?",
            answers: ["Export production - Capture  Fisheries", "Export production - Culture  Fisheries", "Induction of New  Technology and  Modernisation of Processing  Facilities", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        { // 140
            question: "Any species, strain or biotype of plant,  animal or pathogenic agent injurious to  plants and plant products?",
            answers: ["Pollutant", "Pest", "Contaminants", "residue"],
            correct: "Pest"
        },
        {
            question: "Official confinement of regulated articles  for observation and research or for  further inspection, testing and or  treatment?",
            answers: ["Prohibition", "Restriction", "Quarantine", "None of these"],
            correct: "Quarantine"
        },
        {
            question: "Name of the food poisoning pathogen?",
            answers: ["Salmonella", "Listeria", "Both", "None of these"],
            correct: "Both"
        },
        {
            question: "Heavy metals commonly tested in food?",
            answers: ["Mercury", "lead", "Arsenic", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Identify Pesticide?",
            answers: ["Chloramphenicol", "Nitrofurans", "Tetracycline", "None of these"],
            correct: "None of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Identify Pesticide residues?",
            answers: ["BHC", "Aldrin", "Dialdrin", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Three tier surveillance system is being  followed by EIC?",
            answers: ["Monitoring visits", "Supervisory visit", "Corporate Audits", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Export Inspection Agencies (EIAs),  function under?",
            answers: ["FSSAI", "BIS", "DADF", "EIC"],
            correct: "EIC"
        },
        {
            question: "Export Inspection Council of India (EIC)  empowered to?",
            answers: ["Notify commodities", "Establish standards of quality", "Specify the type of quality  control and/or inspection", "All of these"],
            correct: "Notify commodities"
        },
        {
            question: "what are issued by the EIA on request,  after satisfying itself that fish and fishery  products are processed in an approved  establishment/factory vessel having valid  approval number and satisfying that the  requirements of the standards are met?",
            answers: ["Quality certificate", "Lab report", "Health certificate", "None of these"],
            correct: "Health certificate"
        },
        { // 130
            question: "Under the which system, each export  consignment is inspected and tested by  the EIAs?",
            answers: ["In-Process Quality Control  (IPQC) System", "Consignment Wise  Inspection (CWI) System", "Risk communication", "None of these"],
            correct: "Consignment Wise  Inspection (CWI) System"
        },
        {
            question: "This system lays emphasis on the  responsibility of the manufacturers or  processors in ensuring consistency in  quality during all stages of production by  adopting quality control drills and  exercising control on raw materials and  bought-out components, manufacturing  process, packing and final testing?",
            answers: ["In-Process Quality Control  (IPQC) System", "Hazard analysis", "Risk communication", "None of these"],
            correct: "In-Process Quality Control  (IPQC) System"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the homogenised product  prepared from milk fat, non-fat-milk  solids and water. Recombined milk shall  be pasteurised and shall show a negative  Phosphatase test?",
            answers: ["Toned milk", "Double toned milk", "Full cream milk", "Recombined milk"],
            correct: "Double toned milk"
        },
        {
            question: "CEPC full form?",
            answers: ["Cashew export promotion  council of India", "Export council of India", "Common energy council", "Coffee enrich product  commission"],
            correct: "Cashew export promotion  council of India"
        },
        {
            question: "It includes the regulation of the quality of  raw materials, assemblies, products and  components; services related to  production; and management,  production, and inspection processes?",
            answers: ["Quality Control", "Risk assessment", "Quality Assurance", "Quality labeling"],
            correct: "Quality Assurance"
        },
        {
            question: "Remains of Pesticides and remain of  veterinary drugs in the Food Products?",
            answers: ["Microbial load", "Heavy metal load", "Residue", "All of these"],
            correct: "Residue"
        },
        {
            question: "It is the point at which the responsibility  of the foods transfers from shipper to  buyer, or buyer becomes responsible for  the shipment and shipping charges?",
            answers: ["FOB", "DOB", "SPS", "TBT"],
            correct: "FOB"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the ability to trace the history,  use of location of an entity by means of  recorded information. For product, it  refers to the origin of the ingredients, the  history of process applied, the  distribution and location of the product  after delivery?",
            answers: ["Best before", "Use by", "Traceability", "Nutritional labeling"],
            correct: "Traceability"
        },
        {
            question: "What means that part of the container or  package which is intended or likely to be  displayed or presented or shown or  examined by the customer under normal  and customary conditions of display, sale  or purchase of the commodity contained  therein?",
            answers: ["Nutritional label", "Factory board", "Product advertisement", "Principle display board"],
            correct: "Principle display board"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the date which signifies the  end of the estimated period under any  stated storage conditions, after which  product probably will not have quality  attributes normally expected by the  consumers and the food shall not  marketable?",
            answers: ["Date of Packaging", "Expiry", "Best before", "Date of labeling"],
            correct: "Expiry"
        },
        { // 120
            question: "what means the date on which the food  is placed in the immediate container in  which it will be ultimately sold?",
            answers: ["Date of Packaging", "Expiry", "Best before", "Date of labeling"],
            correct: "Date of Packaging"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the date on which the food  becomes the product as described?",
            answers: ["Date of manufacture", "Expiry", "Best Before", "Date of labeling"],
            correct: "Date of manufacture"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the date which signifies the  end of the period under any stated  storage conditions during which the  product shall remain full marketable and  shall retain any specific qualities for  which tacit or express claims have been  made or beyond date the food may still  be perfectly satisfactory?",
            answers: ["Expiry", "Best before", "Disposal date", "Date of production"],
            correct: "Best before"
        },
        {
            question: "what means any representation which  states, suggests or implies that a food has  particular nutritional properties which is  not limited to the energy value but  include proteins, fat carbohydrates,  vitamins and minerals?",
            answers: ["Nutritional Claims", "Nutritional value", "Nutritional fortification", "Nutritional deficiency"],
            correct: "Nutritional Claims"
        },
        {
            question: "what are the persons engaged in food  service operations i.e. Food preparation,  handling and serving. They must be free  from contagious diseases?",
            answers: ["Food suppliers", "Food distributor", "Food Handlers", "None of these"],
            correct: "Food Handlers"
        },
        {
            question: "full form of NCCP?",
            answers: ["National congress of hazard  critical points", "National commission on  plants", "National Codex Contact  Point", "None of these"],
            correct: "National Codex Contact  Point"
        },
        {
            question: "FSSAI recently added standard for new  milk variant is?",
            answers: ["Toned milk", "Double toned milk", "Full cream milk ", "Camel milk"],
            correct: "Camel milk"
        },
        {
            question: "Admixture of any two edible vegetable  oils?",
            answers: ["Non edible", "Blended edible", "Emulsified fat", "Protein"],
            correct: "Blended edible"
        },
        {
            question: "CAL and RAL is?",
            answers: ["Central Agmark Laboratory  and Regional Agmark  Laboratory", "FSSAI authorized laboratory", "BIS authorized laboratory", "APEDA authorized  laboratory"],
            correct: "Central Agmark Laboratory  and Regional Agmark  Laboratory"
        },
        {
            question: "DMI is?",
            answers: ["Directorate of foreign trade", "Directorate of Marketing and  Inspection", "Direct metabolic index", "None of these"],
            correct: "Directorate of Marketing and  Inspection"
        },
        { // 110
            question: "Presence of poisonous or heavy metals in  foods beyond the limits specified in  Rules?",
            answers: ["Metallic contamination", "Pesticide contamination", "Microbial contamination", "Antibiotic  contamination"],
            correct: "Metallic contamination"
        },
        {
            question: "The presence of microorganisms (harmful  bacteria) in foods?",
            answers: ["Heavy metal contamination", "Pesticide contamination", "Microbial contamination", "Antibiotic  contamination"],
            correct: "Microbial contamination"
        },
        {
            question: "Toxic metabolite of Aspergillus spp.  which attacks high protein agricultural  produce like; groundnuts and other nuts  or products?",
            answers: ["Penicillin", "Cyclosporine", "Aflatoxin", "Arsenic"],
            correct: "Aflatoxin"
        },
        {
            question: "the totality of features and  characteristics of a product that bear on  its ability to satisfy stated or implied  needs?",
            answers: ["Quality", "Labeling", "Precision", "Repeatability"],
            correct: "Quality"
        },
        {
            question: "Well awakened about the quality of the  product?",
            answers: ["Quality Conscious", "Quality unconscious", "Quality compliance", "All of these"],
            correct: "Quality Conscious"
        },
        {
            question: "what means any material coming into  contact with Foods which does not  contaminate it so as to render the food  unfit for consumption?",
            answers: ["Packing material", "Food Grade Material", "Heavy metal material", "None of these"],
            correct: "Food Grade Material"
        },
        {
            question: "what is the Bureau of Indian Standards  Certification Mark specified by the  Bureau to represent a particular Indian  Standard?",
            answers: ["Product mark", "Standard mark", "Quality mark", "None of these"],
            correct: "Standard mark"
        },
        {
            question: "ISO is?",
            answers: ["International Organization for  Standardization", "International solar  organization", "International supply  organization", "All of these"],
            correct: "International Organization for  Standardization"
        },
        {
            question: "what means the normal mammary  secretion derived from complete milking  of healthy milch animal, without either  addition thereto or extraction therefrom,  unless otherwise provided in these FSS  regulations and it shall be free from  colostrum?",
            answers: ["Honey", "Oil", "Milk", "Meat"],
            correct: "Milk"
        },
        {
            question: "Contamination of water by discharge of  any sewage, trade effluents, or any other  substances to render water harmful or  injurious to public health?",
            answers: ["Air pollution", "Water Pollution", "Noise pollution", "All of these"],
            correct: "Water Pollution"
        },
        { // 100
            question: "Contrary to or in violation to the rules or  Provisions?",
            answers: ["Contravention", "Conformity", "Compliance", "Improvement notice"],
            correct: "Contravention"
        },
        {
            question: "what means pasteurization, ultrapasteurization, sterilization, ultra-high  temperature treatment or boiling?",
            answers: ["Heat treatment", "Reverse osmosis", "Irradiation", "UV treatment"],
            correct: "Heat treatment"
        },
        {
            question: "Emission or discharge of foul or toxic  substances;gas, liquid or solid?",
            answers: ["Contaminants", "Microbes", "Heavy metal", "Pollutant"],
            correct: "Pollutant"
        },
        {
            question: "Any Infant Food which is partial or total  replacement to mother's milk?",
            answers: ["Milk Powder", "Skim milk powder", "Infant Milk Substitute", "All of these"],
            correct: "Infant Milk Substitute"
        },
        {
            question: "The agents to destroy insects, rodents,  fungi, weeds and other forms of plants or  animal life and are not useful to human  beings?",
            answers: ["Antibiotics", "Pesticide", "Heavy metals", "Veterinary Drug residue"],
            correct: "Pesticide"
        },
        {
            question: "Who does risk assessment for Codex  standards for pesticide residues?",
            answers: ["MICR", "JMPR", "NICS", "JJM"],
            correct: "JMPR"
        },
        {
            question: "In which year was Codex set up?",
            answers: ["1970", "1830", "1953", "1963"],
            correct: "1963"
        },
        {
            question: "FSS Act was amended in?",
            answers: ["2012", "2013", "2016", "None of the above"],
            correct: "None of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "What should be the characteristics of a  food packaging material?",
            answers: ["It protects food from physical,  chemical and biological  hazards", "It withstands mechanical and  thermal stress during  processing and transit", "Material from plastic origin  shall pass through overall  migration limit prescribed  under BIS 91", "All of above"],
            correct: "All of above"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the INS number of Sodium Chloride or Salt?",
            answers: ["IBNS", "INS", "INS 91", "Does not have any INS  number"],
            correct: "Does not have any INS  number"
        },
        { // 90
            question: "Who does risk assessment for Codex  standards for Microbiological  contaminants?",
            answers: ["JEMRA", "JPPAC", "JPALN", "JPLC"],
            correct: "JEMRA"
        },
        {
            question: "Full form of ADI is?",
            answers: ["Acceptable Daily Intake", "Altered Daily Intake", "Acceptable Diet Intake", "None of these"],
            correct: "Acceptable Daily Intake"
        },
        {
            question: "The only difference between frozen  dessert and ice cream is that?",
            answers: ["Frozen dessert use vegetable  fat", "Frozen desert contain milk  fat", "Both", "None of these"],
            correct: "Frozen desert contain milk  fat"
        },
        {
            question: "What is lactose intolerance?",
            answers: ["Difficulty in digesting vitamins", "Difficulty in digesting Lactose", "Difficulty in digesting  proteins", "Difficulty in fat"],
            correct: "Difficulty in digesting Lactose"
        },
        {
            question: "Risk in relation to any article of food,  means?",
            answers: ["Process of product making", "Probability of an adverse  effect on the health of  consumers", "Putting blames on lower  employees", "Providing wrong  information to  consumer"],
            correct: "Probability of an adverse  effect on the health of  consumers"
        },
        {
            question: "Risk assessment means?",
            answers: ["Hazard identification", "Hazard characterisation", "Exposure assessment, and  risk characterisation", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "proprietary and novel food means an  article of food for which?",
            answers: ["Standards have not been  specified but is not unsafe", "Banned food", "FSSAI has no authority to  deal", "Imported food"],
            correct: "Standards have not been  specified but is not unsafe"
        },
        {
            question: "Providing any information or produces  any document that the person knows is  false or misleading?",
            answers: ["No provision in Act to deal  this situation", "Fined and punished with  imprisonment", "FSSAI has no authority to  deal", "None of these"],
            correct: "Fined and punished with  imprisonment"
        },
        {
            question: "FSS Act more effective to crub  adulteration because it guides  manufacturer to control?",
            answers: ["Procurement of raw material", "Production, store and  distribution of food article", "Make consumer aware", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "A toned milk sample assumed having 3%  fat sent to five different laboratory and  results obtained as 2.5, 3.5, 3.1, 2.7, 3.3  what could be reasons for variations?",
            answers: ["Uncertainty of measurements", "Unrepresentative samples", "Food sample attribute due  to storage condition failure  or other reasons", "Any or All of these"],
            correct: "Any or All of these"
        },
        { // 80
            question: "On website of which authority consumer can search FBO information?",
            answers: ["BIS", "Consumer forum", "FSSAI", "Ministry of Health"],
            correct: "FSSAI"
        },
        {
            question: "FFRC full form?",
            answers: ["Food firm registration  certificate", "Food Fortification Resource  Centre", "Food fermentation resource  centre", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Food Fortification Resource  Centre"
        },
        {
            question: "Objectives of FFRC?",
            answers: ["To educate people about the  benefits of fortified foods", "Sensitise states about  fortification of food and  promote them in the Safety  Net Programmes to curb the  incidence of micronutrient  deficiencies", "Provide technical support  especially to small scale food  manufacturers to enable  them to produce fortified  foods", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "Authority set up by the Government of  India in order to ensure sound  development of export trade of India?",
            answers: ["BIS", "EIC", "FSSAI", "None of the above"],
            correct: "EIC"
        },
        {
            question: "Authority set up by the Government of  India in order to ensure sound  development of export trade of India?",
            answers: ["BIS", "EIC", "FSSAI", "None of the above"],
            correct: "EIC"
        },
        {
            question: "FoSTaC - Food Safety Training and  Certification Portal relates to?",
            answers: ["BIS", "EIC", "MPEDA", "FSSAI"],
            correct: "FSSAI"
        },
        {
            question: "FSS Act was amended in?",
            answers: ["2012", "2013", "2016", "None of these"],
            correct: "None of these"
        },
        {
            question: "In which year was Codex set up?",
            answers: ["1970", "1830", "1953", "1963"],
            correct: "1963"
        },
        {
            question: "Food Analyst means an analyst appointed  under?",
            answers: ["Section 3", "Section 45", "Section 61", "Section 71"],
            correct: "Section 45"
        },
        {
            question: "Notified laboratory means any of the  laboratories notified by the Food  Authority under?",
            answers: ["Sub-sections (1) and (2) of  section 43 of the Act", "Section 61", "Section 32", "Section 22"],
            correct: "Sub-sections (1) and (2) of  section 43 of the Act"
        },
        { // 70
            question: "Quality Assurance has advantage in food  safety compliance because of?",
            answers: ["QA aims to prevent defects  with a focus on the process  used to make the product. It  is a proactive quality process", "Top management and every  manager and all areas  (procurement, Production,  Distribution etc) are involved  to ensure safe food", "Everyone on the team  involved in developing the  product is responsible for  quality assurance", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Quality Control has draw backs in food  safety compliance because of?",
            answers: ["Quality control is usually  the responsibility of a  specific team that tests the  product for defects", "The goal of QC is to identify  defects after a product is  developed and before it's  released. Hence chance  rejection and acceptance is  high", "QC aims to identify (and  correct) defects in the  finished product. Quality  control, therefore, is a  reactive process", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Find true statement?",
            answers: ["The goal of QC is to identify  defects after a product is  developed and before it's  released", "The goal of QA is to improve  development and test  processes so that defects do  not arise when the product is  being developed", "Everyone on the team  involved in developing the  product is responsible for  quality assurance", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "Which Section of FSS Act, 2006 describes FSMS?",
            answers: ["Section 16(2)(c) and section  44", "Section 61", "Section 72", "Section 62"],
            correct: "Section 16(2)(c) and section  44"
        },
        {
            question: "What is meant by Food Safety Management Systems?",
            answers: ["System to ensure that food  does not cause adverse  human health effects", "It involve control on raw  material", "It involves control on control  on production, storage,  distribution etc", "All of the above"],
            correct: "System to ensure that food  does not cause adverse  human health effects"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the procedure followed for  launching prosecution?",
            answers: ["Section 22", "Section 32", "Section 67", "Section 48"],
            correct: "Section 67"
        },
        {
            question: "The penalties are specified under which sections of the Act?",
            answers: ["49-67", "32", "22", "2.5"],
            correct: "49-67"
        },
        {
            question: "The functional food and nutraceuticals  are explained in?",
            answers: ["Section 60", "Section 71", "Section 22", "Section 32"],
            correct: "Section 22"
        },
        {
            question: "Does FSSAI recommend some private  laboratories which provide testing  service for food?",
            answers: ["No", "Yes", "No such provision in Act ", "Yes but required  special permission of  state governments"],
            correct: "Yes"
        },
        {
            question: "Does FSSAI provide food testing service  for food manufacturers or importers?",
            answers: ["Yes", "No", "Yes on special request of  manufacturer", "Yes on fee basis"],
            correct: "No"
        },
        { // 60
            question: "Specify the section Under which improvement notice is issued?",
            answers: ["61 of the Act", "90 of the Act", "32 of the Act", "60 of the Act"],
            correct: "32 of the Act"
        },
        {
            question: "How FSS Act will curb increasing food  adulteration?",
            answers: ["Food Safety Management  System, FSMS", "traceability", "recall", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "Which agencies regulate food business in  India?",
            answers: ["FSSAI", "Director General of trade", "Consumer Forum", "Animal Husbandry Department"],
            correct: "FSSAI"
        },
        {
            question: "Which agency is responsible for  investigating food-borne illness and  foreign object complaints?",
            answers: ["FSSAI and State Food  Authorities", "BIS", "EIC agreement", "MPEAD agreement"],
            correct: "FSSAI and State Food  Authorities"
        },
        {
            question: "Which Acts/Orders related to food is  repealed in FSSAI, 2006?",
            answers: ["Prevention of Food  Adulteration Act, 1954", "Fruit Products Order, 1955", "Both", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Both"
        },
        {
            question: "What does FSSAI do?",
            answers: ["Laying down science based  standards for articles of food", "To regulate manufacture,  storage, distribution, sale  and import of food", "To facilitate food safety", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the full form of IAEA?",
            answers: ["India Association of export  authority", "International Atomic Energy  Agency", "International organization of  exporting countries", "None of these"],
            correct: "International Atomic Energy  Agency"
        },
        {
            question: "SPS agreement is a part of the?",
            answers: ["FSSAI", "BIS", "WTO agreement", "MPEAD agreement"],
            correct: "WTO agreement"
        },
        {
            question: "Schedule 4 of FSS Licensing Regulations  has how many parts?",
            answers: ["2 parts", "6 parts", "5 parts", "9 parts"],
            correct: "5 parts"
        },
        {
            question: "What is a certification mark employed on  agricultural products in India, assuring  that they conform to a set of standards  approved by the Directorate of  Marketing and Inspection, an agency of  the Government of India?",
            answers: ["FSSAI", "EIC", "AGMARK", "Hall mark"],
            correct: "AGMARK"
        },
        { // 50
            question: "Food items targeted for fortification?",
            answers: ["BIS", "FSSAI", "DADF", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above",
            description: "doubt"
        },
        {
            question: "Which authority initiated mobile units  for food testing to reach out to  consumers?",
            answers: ["BIS", "FSSAI", "DADF", "All of the above"],
            correct: "FSSAI"
        },
        {
            question: "Which of the following is not an artificial  sweetener?",
            answers: ["Saccharin", "Aspartame", "Sugar", "Neotame"],
            correct: "Sugar"
        },
        {
            question: "What type of fats are unhealthy?",
            answers: ["Polyunsaturated", "Polysaccharide", "Saturated and trans fat", "Monosaturated"],
            correct: "Saturated and trans fat"
        },
        {
            question: "Salt is iodized to prevent?",
            answers: ["Marasmus", "Goitre", "Pellagra", "Anaemia"],
            correct: "Goitre"
        },
        {
            question: "The article of consisting, wholly or in  part, of any filthy, putrid, rotten,  decomposed or diseased animal  substance is?",
            answers: ["Misbranding", "Substandard food", "Unsafe food", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Unsafe food"
        },
        {
            question: "Sub-standard food means?",
            answers: ["It does not meet the specified  standards but not so as to  render the article of food  unsafe", "Unsafe food", "Manufactured without  license", "All of the above"],
            correct: "It does not meet the specified  standards but not so as to  render the article of food  unsafe"
        },
        {
            question: "Primary food means an article of food?",
            answers: ["Produce of agriculture or horticulture", "Processed food", "Food prepared by mixing  ingredients", "All of the above"],
            correct: "Produce of agriculture or horticulture"
        },
        {
            question: "Premises under FSS act include?",
            answers: ["Shop", "Hotel", "Food canteens", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "Misbranded food means an article of food?",
            answers: ["Offered or promoted for sale  with false, misleading or  deceptive claims", "Food prepared without  license", "Food contain insect", "Food contain extraneous matter"],
            correct: "Offered or promoted for sale  with false, misleading or  deceptive claims"
        },
        { // 40
            question: "A1 and A2 are types of?",
            answers: ["Honey", "Water", "Milk", "Fish"],
            correct: "Milk"
        },
        {
            question: "Vitamins used to fortified milk?",
            answers: ["Vitamin A", "Vitamin D", "Vitamin C", "Both Vitamin A and D"],
            correct: "Both Vitamin A and D"
        },
        {
            question: "What is meant by SNF?",
            answers: ["Fat part of milk", "Water in milk", "Protein in milk", "Part of milk without water and Fat"],
            correct: "Part of milk without water and Fat"
        },
        {
            question: "Chemical name of Ajinomoto is?",
            answers: ["Ascorbic Acid", "Tryptophan", "Calciferol", "Monosodium Glutamate"],
            correct: "Monosodium Glutamate"
        },
        {
            question: "BMI is the acronym of?",
            answers: ["Body Mass Index", "Body matter mass", "Body meal diet", "Blood mass index"],
            correct: "Body Mass Index"
        },
        {
            question: "BIS stands for?",
            answers: ["Bharat Import Standards", "Bureau of Indian Standards", "Bureau of Indian System", "Bureau of International  Standards"],
            correct: "Bureau of Indian Standards"
        },
        {
            question: "Food Safety and Standards Act, 2006 was  operationalised on?",
            answers: ["5th August, 2011", "5th August, 2007", "5th August, 2012", "5th August, 2013"],
            correct: "5th August, 2011"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the full form of EU?",
            answers: ["England Union", "Export Union", "European Union", "All of the above"],
            correct: "European Union"
        },
        {
            question: "FSSAI operates under which Ministry?",
            answers: ["Ministry of Agriculture", "Ministry of consumer", "Ministry of commerce ", "Ministry of Health and  Family Welfare"],
            correct: "Ministry of Health and  Family Welfare"
        },
        {
            question: "Full form of HACCP?",
            answers: ["Hazard automatic control  point", "Hazard authority critical  control point", "Hazard Analysis Critical  Control Point", "All of the above"],
            correct: "Hazard Analysis Critical  Control Point"
        },
        { // 30
            question: "What does FMCG stand for?",
            answers: ["Fast Moving Consumer Goods  industry", "Fast Moving Cooking Goods  industry", "Fast Moving Coal Goods  industry", "Fast Moving cement  industry"],
            correct: "Fast Moving Consumer Goods  industry"
        },
        {
            question: "Secretariat of FAO is located in which  city?",
            answers: ["Rome", "USA", "France", "Japan"],
            correct: "Rome"
        },
        {
            question: "WTO regulates?",
            answers: ["FSSAI standard", "Codex standards", "BIS standard", "EIC standard"],
            correct: "Codex standards"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the full form of TBT?",
            answers: ["Total barrier toll", "Technical Barriers to Trade", "Technical battle to court", "Thermal Bacterial tilt"],
            correct: "Technical Barriers to Trade"
        },
        {
            question: "What is FIFO?",
            answers: ["First In First out", "First out Last In", "Food Inspection", "Food officer"],
            correct: "First In First out"
        },
        {
            question: "Full form of EIC?",
            answers: ["Export Inspection Council of  India", "Export Inspection Agency", "Export Inquiry Council", "None of these"],
            correct: "Export Inspection Council of  India"
        },
        {
            question: "Food Safety and Standards Act, 2006 was  notified on?",
            answers: ["24th August, 2006", "2nd October 2006", "15th August 2006", "26th January 2006"],
            correct: "24th August, 2006"
        },
        {
            question: "Nutritional information is not required  for which one of the following products?",
            answers: ["Pickles", "Soft drinks", "Bread", "Biscuit"],
            correct: "Pickles"
        },
        {
            question: "What are the different categories of  license?",
            answers: ["Registration", "State license", "Central License", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        {
            question: "FBO needs to apply for Central Or State  License will depend on?",
            answers: ["The nature of a business", "Its turnover", "Area of operation", "All of these"],
            correct: "All of these"
        },
        { // 20
            question: "In food industry Quality Assurance is?",
            answers: ["Procurement activity", "Production activity", "Distribution activity", "A complete system to  assure the quality of  products"],
            correct: "A complete system to  assure the quality of  products"
        },
        {
            question: "What is the Purpose of FSMS?",
            answers: ["To ensure the manufacture", "storage", "distribution and sale of safe  food", "All of the above"],
            correct: "All of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "What is meant by Food Safety  Management Systems (FSMS)?",
            answers: ["System to ensure that food  does not cause adverse  human health effects", "It involve control on raw  material", "It involves control on control  on production, storage,  distribution etc.", "All of the above"],
            correct: "System to ensure that food  does not cause adverse  human health effects"
        },
        {
            question: "Specify the reason of ban on import of  milk products from China?",
            answers: ["To stop mercury  contamination", "To stop heavy metal  contamination", "To stop antibiotics  contamination", "To stop melamine  contamination"],
            correct: "To stop melamine  contamination"
        },
        {
            question: "How do consumer complain about food  bought from a shop or restaurant?",
            answers: ["should complain to the Food  Safety Officer", "Designated Officer", "Food Safety Commissioner  of the State", "Any of the above"],
            correct: "Any of the above"
        },
        {
            question: "What should consumers do if they have a  product that has been recalled?",
            answers: ["Return product to company", "Complaint to police", "Complaint to Food authority", "Complaint to health  ministry"],
            correct: "Return product to company"
        },
        {
            question: "What is a food recall?",
            answers: ["Action taken to remove a  marketed food", "Action taken to sale the food  on priority", "Action taken to final dispose  of food by company", "All of the above"],
            correct: "Action taken to remove a  marketed food"
        },
        {
            question: "What is a food recall?",
            answers: ["Action taken to remove a  marketed food", "Action taken to sale the food  on priority", "Action taken to final dispose  of food by company", "All of the above"],
            correct: "Action taken to remove a  marketed food"
        },
        {
            question: "How can consumer know whether a  particular food additive can be used in a  food product in India?",
            answers: ["On EIC website", "On DADF website", "on FSSAI website", "on MPEDA website"],
            correct: "on FSSAI website"
        },
        {
            question: "Organic food means?",
            answers: ["Food and food ingredients  composed of or containing  genetically modified or  engineered organisms", "Food products that have  been produced in  accordance with specified  organic production standards", "Both", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Food products that have  been produced in  accordance with specified  organic production standards"
        },
        { // 10
            question: "Who issues improvement notice?",
            answers: ["FSO", "Designated Office", "Central food authority", "Health ministry"],
            correct: "Designated Office"
        },
        {
            question: "Do State governments have to comply  with the requirements of the Food Act  2006?",
            answers: ["No", "Yes", "Require permission of  Central government", "Required permission of  central health ministry"],
            correct: "Yes"
        },
        {
            question: "Is there a registration fee required under  FSSAI?",
            answers: ["Yes, Rs. 100", "Yes, Rs. 50", "No fee", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Yes, Rs. 100"
        },
        {
            question: "Does FSSAI provide training to food  business operators?",
            answers: ["Yes", "No", "This is not a mandate of  FSSA", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Yes"
        },
        {
            question: "How consumer analyze the samples of  food under FSSAI?",
            answers: ["Directly by approaching  authority", "Consumer cannot analyse  the sample", "Permission of police is  required", "None of the above"],
            correct: "Directly by approaching  authority"
        },
        {
            question: "Any substance not intentionally added to  food, which is present in such food as a  result of the production manufacture,  processing, preparation, treatment,  packing, packaging, transport or holding  of such food or as a result of  environmental contamination is called?",
            answers: ["Additive", "Supplement", "Ingredient", "Contaminant"],
            correct: "Contaminant"
        },
        {
            question: "Which term is applied to all stomach and  intestinal disturbances due to food  contaminated with certain  microorganisms or to their toxins?",
            answers: ["Food allergy", "Food poisoning", "Food infection", "Food spoilage"],
            correct: "Food poisoning"
        },
        {
            question: "Full form of FAO is?",
            answers: ["Forest and Agriculture Office", "Food Administration  Organization", "Food and Agricultural  Organisation", "All of these"],
            correct: "Food and Agricultural  Organisation"
        },
        {
            question: "Full form of FSSAI is?",
            answers: ["State food Authority", "Food Safety and Standards  Authority of India", "Food Safety Association of  India", "None of these"],
            correct: "Food Safety and Standards  Authority of India"
        },
        {
            question: "What Does Green Dot on food packet  stand for?",
            answers: ["Vegetarian food", "Non-Vegetarian Food", "Organic Food", "Fortified Food"],
            correct: "Vegetarian food"
        },
        
]